<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?> 
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?> 
<TEI xmlns='http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0'>
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>HEMU Conservatoire de Genève - Programme de concert</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <editionStmt>
        <edition>TEI P5.1 Edition</edition>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>
            <persName>Claudio Bacciagaluppi</persName>
            <persName>Paolo Boschetti</persName>
            <persName>Laurent Pugin</persName>
            <persName>Violeta Struijk van Bergen</persName>
            <persName>Rodolfo Zitellini</persName>
            <date when='2016-01'>Janvier 2016</date>
          </resp>
          <name>Bureau Suisse du RISM</name>
        </respStmt>
      </editionStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>
          <orgName xml:base='http://www.rism-ch.org'>Bureau Suisse du RISM</orgName>
        </publisher>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <idno type='collection'>ch_gc</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>
            <date when='19090526'>26/05/1909</date>
             [sans titre] 
          </title>
          <series>None</series>
          <placeName>Inconnu</placeName>
          <orgName role='holding'>
             Bibliothèque du Conservatoire de Musique de Genève; 
            <link target='http://www.cmusge.ch/contact_bibliotheque'/>
          </orgName>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <!-- all the content of the program in one paragraph -->
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_07/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_07-0843.tif'/>
        <date when='19090526'/>
        <name key='Beethoven, Ludwig van' type='person' role='cmp'>Beethoven, Ludwig van</name>
        <name key='Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus' type='person' role='cmp'>Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus</name>
        <name key='Meyerbeer, Giacomo' type='person' role='cmp'>Meyerbeer, Giacomo</name>
        <name key='Mendelssohn Bartholdy, Felix' type='person' role='cmp'>Mendelssohn Bartholdy, Felix</name>
        <name key='Händel, Georg Friedrich' type='person' role='cmp'>Händel, Georg Friedrich</name>
        <name key='Spohr, Louis' type='person' role='cmp'>Spohr, Louis</name>
        <name key='Schubert, Franz' type='person' role='cmp'>Schubert, Franz</name>
        <name key='Rossini, Gioachino' type='person' role='cmp'>Rossini, Gioachino</name>
        <name key='Haydn, Joseph' type='person' role='cmp'>Haydn, Joseph</name>
        <name key='Himmel, Friedrich Heinrich' type='person' role='cmp'>Himmel, Friedrich Heinrich</name>
        <name key='Wagner, Richard' type='person' role='cmp'>Wagner, Richard</name>
        <name key='Gounod, Charles-François' type='person' role='cmp'>Gounod, Charles-François</name>
        <title/>
        <placeName key='s.l.'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿       PR06RAMME-REPERT0IRE
   \â STAFF-MUSIQUE
         INTERNATIONALE de LONDRES
          SOUS Id DIRECTION DU COLONEL SIMPSON
Quartier Général national :
BERTîE
Directeur des Réunions : COMMISSAIRE W. J. MAC ALONflN
                 ou---
Lieut,-Colonel GAUHTLETT
ssg)
CHEF DE FATÎFARE : COLONEL MITCHELL
]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_07/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_07-0844.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿ La ?»Ja£f*AIusique
de l’Armée du Salut
Tournée en Suisse du ry au j i V\(ai 1909
     La Fanfare d’Etat-Major de Londres fait actuellement sa troisième tournée en Suisse. Les Réunions et les Concerts qu’elle a tenus en 1906 et en 1907, ont béni autant que charmé tous ceux qui ont eu le privilège d’entendre sa musique, ses chants et ses témoignages, et les Fanfaristes eux-mêmes en ont été grandement intéressés et réjouis.
     Quoique la Staff-Musique ait été sollicitée de visiter d’autres pays depuis lors, elle revient en Suisse, et c’est la seule campagne qu'elle puisse faire cette année en dehors de l’Angleterre. Nous sommes assurés que cette tournée aura autant de succès, si ce n’est davantage, que les années précédentes.
     La Staff-Musique se compose de 33 officiers d’Etat-Major, attachés au Quartier-Général de l’Armée du Salut à Londres, et qui, en consacrant à l’étude le temps de loisir dont ils peuvent disposer, ont acquis un haut degré de supériorité.
     Ces fanfaristes ne sont pas des musiciens de profession, ils emploient leurs dons simplement en vue d’attirer l’attention sur l’Evan-gile glorieux de Jésus-Christ et se réjouissent d’amener de cette manière des milliers de personnes à la connaissance du salut.
     Cette satisfaction-li est la seule récompense qu’ils reçoivent de leur œuvre musicale et évangélique ; du reste il en est de même pour les dix-neuf mille autres musiciens de l’Armée du Salut. Ils ne demandent aucune autre rémunération.
     Il 11e faut pas oublier que la musique jouée par la Staff-Musique, si même elle revêt parfois un caractère profane, est cependant pleine d’un sentiment religieux ; l’Armée, comme on le sait déjà, adapte un grand nombre de ses chants à des mélodies qui paraissent s’approprier au but qu’elle se propose.
     La musique que la fanfare exécute a été entièrement arrangée et dans bien des cas composée par des salutistes; elle est imprimée dans les ateliers de l’Armée à Londres où l’on fabrique également les instruments et les uniformes des Fanfaristes.
     Nous rappelons encore que le but de la Fanfare est essentiellement évangélique; sa musique contient un message spirituel pour tous ; une exhortation pour les enfants de Dieu à redoubler d’efforts à Son service et un message d’avertissement et d’invitation aux inconvertis.]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_07/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_07-0845.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿>-®-l
MARCHES
Les «Marches instrumentales » suivantes, composées par des Salutistes, ont pour thèmes les pays, les villes ou les sujets mentionnés.
1.	France. Introduisant « La Marseillaise ».
2.	GermanY* Introduisant « La Wacht ara Rhein ».
3.	Australia. Composée par un Officier attaché au Quartier-Gé-
       néral de Melbourne, Australie.
4.	New-Zealand. Composée par le Directeur de l’une des fanfa-
       res de Christchurch, Nouvelle Zélande.
5.	The Warrior.
6.	The Cornet.
7.	The Trumpet.
8.	The Drum.
9.	The Flag.
10.	The Proclamation. Composée par le Sous-Chef de fanfare
      du corps de Regent-Hall à Londres.
11.	The Great Review.
12.	The Standard Bearer.
13.	The first-prize March, 1909. Composée et arrangée par
un jeune fanfariste de l’Armée du Salut à Londres.
14.	Good choice.
15.	Under the Colours. Composée par un jeune fanfariste du
      corps de Chalk Farm à Londres.
16.	The Kettering March. Staff-Captain Goldsmith, de la
       Staff-Band.
17.	The Shields March. Composée par le Directeur de la fanfare
       du corps de South Shields, Nord de l’Angleterre.
18.	The Tyneside March.
19.	The Leyton March. Composée par le Sous-Chef de fanfare
      du corps de Leyton à Londres.
20.	The Cadet.
21.	Perseverance.
22.	Chicago. Composée par le Directeur de l’une des fanfares de
       Chicago, Etats-Unis.
— 3
MORCEAUX CHOISIS
Morceaux choisis, hymnes, etc., renfermant des fragments d’œuvres des grands maîtres et arrangés par le ‘Département Musical de
l’iArmée du Salut
 1.	Seleetion. a. Beethoven, b. Mozart, c. Meyerbeer. d. Mendel-
       sohn.
 2.	Seleetion. a. Hândel. b. Spohr. c. Schubert, d. Beethoven.
      e. Rossini./. Haydn.
 3.	Hynin. « Supplication » (Beethoven).
 4.	Hynin. « The Wondrous Cross » (Himmel).
 5.	Hymn. « Oh! Thou who driest the Mourner’s tear » (Haydn).
 6.	Mareh. (Wagner.)
SÉLECTIONS
d’airs nationaux, de mélodies de l’Armée du Salut et autres
 1.	Ail Nations. Airs nationaux de l’Amérique, de la Norvège,
       des Indes, de la Suède, de la France, de l’Allemagne, du Japon, du Danemark, de la Hollande, de la Belgique, de la Grande-Bretagne. L’Armée est actuellement à l’œuvre dans 54 pays différents et prêche l’Evangile en 26 langues.
 2.	International Eehoes. Sélection nouvelle des mélodies de
       toutes nations.
 3.	Swiss Melodies. Sélection de mélodies populaires suisses,
      accueillie avec enthousiasme dans la dernière tournée de la Staff-Musique en Suisse.
 4.	Songs of Holland. Sélections d’airs nationaux hollandais.
 5.	Jésus lives. Choix de chants au sujet de la mort, du tombeau
       et de la résurrection du Sauveur.
       a. He lives. b. Christ the Lord is risen to-day. c. Victory o’er death. d. Jésus lives. e. Up from the grave He arose.
 6.	Songs of Heaven. Chants parlant du ciel et des joies des
       rachetés.
       a. The Song of Heaven. b. There’s a beautiful land on High.
       c.	Up in that City paved with Gold. d. It’s. true there’s a beautiful City.
 7.	The City of God. Chants parlant des gloires de la Cité céleste.
       a.	The Beautiful City of Light. b. I have read of a beautiful City. c. Beautiful Zion. d. Where the Sun never sets. e. Up in the golden City.]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_07/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_07-0846.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿8.	Songs of Joy* Chants parlant du bonheur de ceux qui sui-
        vent Christ.
        a. Jo'y, joy, joy. b. He gave me joy. c. Wonderful joy. d. A Life of joy. e. Joy for to-morrow./. Sing with joy.
9.	Hebrew Melodies. Sélection de vieilles mélodies hébraïques.
        a. The Song of Miriam. b. First Fruits, c. The 24,h Psalm.
        d.	Wailing for the destruction of Jérusalem. £. Welcome to the Sabbath./. The Feast of Lights.
10.	Hebrew Melodies. Sélection de vieilles mélodies hébraïques
        employées aux grandes fêtes juives.
        a. Leoni. b. God passing Moses. c. The Schofar Cal 1. d. The Feast of Solemn Assembly. e. The Feast of Trumpets.
11.	Songs of Freedom. Parlant de la liberté de ceux qui ont été
        délivrés de l’esclavage du péché.
        a. Free! b. Glory, I’m free. c. Ncwl am free. d. Perfect Freedom have I.
12.	Memories of Childhood. Sélection de chants d’enfants au
        sujet de Jésus, du Ciel, dont le plus beau est certainement le Solo de Cornet. — « I think when I read that sweet Story ot Old ».
13.	Merey- Arrangée parStaff-Captain Goldsmith delà Staff-Musique.
       a. There is Mercy in Jésus, b. The great Physician. c. At the Cross when a Soul is Pleading. d. I’m glad Fin ready.
        e.	Who’s that knocking at the door.
       La finale pathétique donne la description d’une âme frappant à la porte de la grâce, mais trop tard. Finale. « Knocking, knocking, Then it’s no use knocking any more. »
14.	Battle Strains. Arrangé parStaff-Captain Goldsmith de la Staff-
        Musique, parle du combat contre le péché, de la victoire et delà récompense finale du soldat, introduisant :
        a.	Soldier rouse Thee ! b. The Call to Arms. b. et c. Battl-ing for the Lord. d. The Soldier’s Rest. e. Soldiers of the Mighty One.
15.	My Saviour. a. A never faiIing Friend. b. My Saviour suffer-
       ed on the Tree. c. Thou art a Mighty Saviour. d. Oh ! such a Saviour ! e. My Saviour’s still the same.
16.	Peaee. a. Perfect peace 1 enjoy. b. Peace. c. Jésus came with
        Peace to me. d. Perfect Peace’. e. In perfect Peace./. At Peace with God.
17.	Songs of Praise. a. Oh! what shall I do my Saviour to praise.
       b.	Praise Him more and more. c. Now in a Song of grateful Praise. d. Praise Him for ever. e. Praise God l’m savèd. /. Praise God for what He’s done for me.
18.	Redemption. a. I am rèdeemed. b. Oh ! what a Redeemer.
19- The Beautiful Stream. Parle de la source coulant pour
        purifier le péché.
       11.	Oh ! have you not heard of the beautiful Stream. b. Corne to tliis beautiful Stream. c. Still it flows. d. Oh! corne to this beautiful Stream.
20.	Songs of Comfort. a. Corne ye disconsolate. b. Don’t forget
Hc’s near thee. c. I will guide thee. d. He wipes the tear from
       every eye.
21.	Echoes from Calvary. Parlant des souffrances, de la mort,
       du tombeau et de la résurrection du Seigneur Jésus-Christ.
       a.	Gethsemane. b. When I survey. c. At Calvary. d. At the Tomb of our Lord. e. The Résurrection.
22.	Guide me oh Thou Great Jehovah. a. Guide me. b. The
       Verge of Jorden. c. The Cry&tal Foutain.
23.	Prineethorpe. Arrangé par le Major Ostby, de la Suède. Ré-
       flexion sur les expériences passées de l’âme, et ses espérances glorieuses.
       11.	Méditation, b. Fraises to our King. c. Dark and ever darker was the wintry past. d. Clearer still, and ever clearer, dawns the light from Heaven. e. Higher then, and higher, bear the ransomed Soul.
24.	Songs of Heaven. a. Roll Jordan, roll. b. And when I reach
       those pearly Gates, c. There is a City bright. d. Meeting in Heaven. e. When the Roll is called up yonder./. My beautiful Home.
25.	International Eehoes. a.'Danemark, To war for God. b. Ca-
        nada, The one I love. c. Suède, The precious Fountain. d. Etats-Unis, Everybody has a work to do. e. Norvège, March on.
HYMNES, etc.
1.	Jerusalem, My happy Home.
           Jérusalem, my happy Home,
            Name ever dear to me ;
            When shall my labours have an end ?
            In Joy and Peace with Thee ?
           Oh, when, thou City of my God,
             Shall 1 thy courts ascend ?
            Where congrégations ne’er break up,
            And Sabbaths have no end ?
There happier bow’rs than Eden’s bloom,
            No sin nor sorrow know :
            Blest Seat ! through rude and stormy scenes,
            I onward press to you.]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_07/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_07-0847.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿             Jerusalem ! Jerusalem !
           Name ever dear to me!
    Why should 1 shrink at pain or woe ?
             Or feel at death dismay ?
    l’ve Canaan’s goodly land in view,
            And realms of endless day.
           Jerusalem ! my happy Home!
             My soul still pants for thee ;
   Then shall my labours have an end,
            When I thy joys shall see.
            Jerusalem ! Jerusalem !
            Name ever dear to me !
            Name ever dear to me !
2.	Before Jehovah’s awful Throne.
                Before Jehovah’s awful Throne Ye nations bow with sacred joy.
3.	When I survey the wondrous cross. (Wareham.)
                When I survey the wondrous cross On which the Prince of Glory died My richest gain I count but loss,
                And pour contempt on ail my pride.
4.	Take my life and let it be. (Nottingham.)
                   'l'ake my life, and let it be Consecrated, Lord to Thee,
   Take my moments and my days,
                  Let then flow in ceaseless praise.
5.	Rock of Ages cleft for me. (Rousseau.)
            Rock of Ages cleft for me Let me hide myself in Thee Let the Water and the Blood
           From Thy wounded side which flowed Be of sin the double cure
            Save from wrath and make nie pure.
6.	Jésus Lover of my Soul.
                 Jésus Lover of my soul Let me to Thy bosom fly,
                 While the nearer Waters roll While the Tempest still is high.
               Hide me, oh my Saviour hide Till the storm of Life be past Safe into the Haven <*uide Oh ! receive my Soul at last.
7.	Lead kindly Light.
     (Voir Musique vocale, N° 10 Quartette.)

              —	7 — MUSIQUE VOCALE
 CHŒURS DES FANFARISTES AVEC ACCOMPAGNEMENT D’INSTRUMENTS
 1.	Who with me will a soldier be?
         Who with me will a Soldier be,
              In the Army which the Lord delights to bless ?
         With the cross before we will march to war
              In the cause of freedom and righteousness.
 2.	IMazareth. (Gounod.)
         Jésus, loved redeemer, unto us impart
               Lowliness of spirit, righteousness of heart.
 3.	The Soldier’s Chorus. (Gounod.)
      Ail Praise and Glory to God on high,
      Who gave the Saviour for us to die ;
     Now we are fully redeemed from sin,
 And ready to fight or ready to die men’s soûls to win.
      Sin is mighty and strong, and who can be.free ?
      See how eager the throng for sin’s gaiety !
     Thanks be unto our God, He lias made a way,
     By giving His Son, He victory has won,
     And now we can say —
 Oh! what wondrous love the Saviour has for ev’ry guilty, helpless sinner, Rest and peace heoffers free to ail who from theirsins will turn away ; Able now to save and break the bonds that strong have been your He cannot fail, but shall prevail,	[soul to hinder,
 His mighty power can liberate the fetter’d soul from sin to-day ;
 He cannot fail, but shall prevail,
 His mighty power can liberate the fetter’d soul from sin to-day.
 4.	Glad Times.
 Tell it abroad, Good is the Lord,
                     Let us be glad, let us rejoice Singing with heart and voice,
                   For He is worthy dominion to receive.
 CHŒURS DES FANFARISTES
 OCTETTES VOCAUX
 Staff Captait1 %eardon Lieui.-Col. Le Huit Adjudant Fuller Bandsman Buckman]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_07/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_07-0848.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿             — 8 —
5- Praise ye the Lord.
                Praise ye the Lord ! Praise the Lord He’s worthy to be praised ;
                So raise your voice in cheerful song today. Raise your voice in cheerful song,
                 Praise, praise, praise, praise !
               He is our God, the mighty King of Kings,
At whose bright présence darkness Aies away. Praise ye the Lord ! Praise ye the Lord !
6.	Remember me.
           When storms around are sweeping,
           When lone my watch l’m keeping,
              ’Mid fires of evil falling,
             ’Mid tempters voices calling,
Remember me, O Mighty One. (repeat.)
            When walking on life’s océan,
             Control its raging motion ;
            When from its dangers shrinking,
            When in its dread deeps sinking,
           Remember me, O Mighty One. (repeat.)
            When weight of sin oppresses,
            When dark despair distresses,
              Ail thro’ the Life that’s mortal,
             And when I pass death’s portai,
Remember me, O Mighty One. (repeat.)
7.	March on.
             We find delight in fighting for Jésus,
            Grand is the War for our Redeemer!
             Our foes may threaten. but love’s glorious flame Burns within our hearts for him.
            Forward go ! Forward go ! March on !
            Love to God makes us go to fight,
             Glory soon will be given.
            In the land where they walk in white,
            Endless peace is in Heaven.
            We stand for truth and righteousncss,
            For God we shed our blood,
             We’re passing through this earth’s djstress To rest and peace with God.
              We’ll sing for ever of this love,
            And of the grâce we daily prove,
             That helps us in the fight to win.
             O	Soldier of the iiving God,
               March on !

9
B. Onward March.
     Onward, onw;rd, march to victory !
      Though the foe be very near, yet our hearts have not a fear. We will march, and the song of victory sing,
      For we battle ior the right,
     Leaning on our Saviour’s might,
     To His banner we will cling, and boldly sing,
     Onward, on we march to Glorv !
     With our banners flying, flying everywhere;
     We’re marching onward, onward now to Glory!
     Hark the Songs!
      Hark the songs of victory swelling o’er the battlefield !
      And when this life is o’er and vict’ry won,
     We’ll up to Glory go, our hearts made white as snow, l or Jésus died that we to Heaven might go,
     And be for ever there with the Holy ones.
9.	The Army Drum.
     One day a band of Arniy Soldiers
        Were Sounding aloud their drum, drum, drum, drum, As through the Streets they marched along And far above the sound of song The noisy drum said conte — (répéter 8 fois)
     The noisy drum said Conie !
9>. Negro Plantation Song. « Who built the Ark. »
 QUATUORS VOCAUX Slaff Captai» ‘Rcardon. Lient.-Col. Le Bult. ‘Brigadier Hurren. Staff Captain Goldstnith.
10.	Lead kindly Light.
         Lead kindly Light, amidst the encircling gloom,
  Lead Thou me 011 !
        The niaht is dark. and I am far from Home Lead I hou me on !
         Keep Thou my feet ; I do not ask to sec The distant scene : 011e step enough for me.
         I was not ever thus, nor prayed that Thou,
  Should’st lead me on ;
  I lov’d to choo.se and see my path ; but now,
  Lead Thou me on !
          I lov’d the garish day ; and, spite of fears,
  Pride rul’d my will, remember not past years,]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_07/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_07-0849.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿           So	long Thy pow’r hast blest me, sure it still Will lead me on.
          O’er moor and mountain, crag and torrent, till The nighl is gone,
           And with the morn, those angel faces smile,
           Whicb 1 have lov'd long since, and lost awhile.
n. Providence.
           Oh! how entraining life’s prospect seemed
          As on its springtime the Sun brighthy beamed The song of the birds to my heart seemed to say Have ne’er a fear. ’twill be thus on the way.
           False was the message 1 learned, oh! so soon,
          For shadows had gathered and deepened e’er noon And but for the guidance from Heaven bestowed,
           I should have wandered far off the road.
Chorus: Too wise to err, too good to be unkind My Saviour leads 1 follow close behind Whate ’er befalleth Fil trust Him to the end Heaven’s chiefest glory, earth’s dearest friend.
DUOS VOCAUX Brigadier Hurren. Slaff Captain ‘Rjardon.
12.	We are happy, glad and free.
We are happy, glad and free,
                  We were blind but now we see, Now our hearts are full of joy,
                  And new songs our lips employ ; Jésus has given liberty,
Sinner, He’ll do the same for thee.
13.	To heal the broken heart.
A Hiding-place from every storm,
A shelter that defends from harm,
               A light that cheers the path of gloom, Is Christ to ail who to Him come,
O	wounded heart thy sorrow bring,
               For thou may’st gain relief from Him Who gave His life so to redeem Each grieving soul o’erthrown by sin.
           To heal the broken heart lie came,
           To free the captive from his chain,
          The Blood He spilt when He was slain Brings guilty sinners home to God.
— II —
               O	trembling, thy heavy weight Of guilt just now to Jésus take,
               He shed His blood that He might make A cleansing fountain for thy sake.
               Thy bonds shall break, O captive one,
                For Christ to set'thee free has come,
               He waits to give the precious boon,
               The freedom thou hast sought so long.
14.	All’s well.
                Now in a song of grateful praise To my dear Lord will I raise With ail His Saints Fil join to tell My Jésus hath done ail things well.
             SOLI VOCAUX. Slnff Cnptain Réunion.
15.	A plea for pardon.
Guilty, guilty,
Nothing have I to bring,
Nothing to gain Thy Grâce Lord,
Nothing but a life of sin ;
Grieving, mourning,
Over a wasted past,
Here dear Saviour,
                         Myself at Thy feet I cast.
         In Thy heart there’s Mercy, in Thy love there’s hope Thou wilt raise the fallen, Thou wilt lift me up, Guilty helpless, I to Thine arms now fly
        Save, oh save me, a sinner condemned to die.
Trembling, hoping,
Flying from dark despair,
Have I not heard that Thou, Lord Heedeth the sinner’s prayer ?
Groaning, bleeding,
Dying on Calvary,
                  There Thou purchased Salvation and Life for me.
Love so boundless,
Henceforth my ail shall claim,
Bought by Thy Blood so precious.
Saved by Thy grief and pain ;
I	can ne’er, Lord,
                       Pay Thee the debt I owe,
But my life, Lord,
                          In service for Thee shall flow.]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_07/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_07-0850.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿                     —	12 —
            16.	Calvary.
                    O	Calvarv ! o Calvary ! the thorn, the crown. the spear.
                         ’Tis there th'v love, my Jésus, in flowing wounds appear
                    O	depths of love and mercy, to those dear wounds 1 tiee
  1	was a guilty sinner, but Jésus died for me.
           17.	The Sufferings of Jésus.
                            Whene’er I stop to ponder O’ er the story of the Cross,
                              My soul is filled whith wonder,
 And in amazement lost ;
                              To think that Christ for such as me Gave up His life 011 Calvary,
                              That I from sin might be set free He there for mé was slain.
                       For me my Lord was slain,
                        For me he suffered pain,
 He bled and died, was crucified,
                        That I might pardon gain ;
                       For me my Lord was slain,
                       For me He bore the shame,
                         ’Twas for my guilt His blood was spilt.
                       Oh! Glory to His name !
                             I	see Him in the Garden,
                              And 1 liear the prayer He prayed When sin, the world’s great burden,
 Upon the Lord was laid,
                             « Oh, let this cup pass now from Me, »
  He cries in bitter agony.
                              « Yet not My will, but Thine to be, »
                            With God the Saviour pleads.
           iS.	The Vétéran.
                            Just wheel my chair to the window And wide the casement fling,
                             For I want to see the Army As they mardi along and sing,
                            So	fetch me my old red guernsey And set me upon my feet For The Army Band is coming;
                               Don’t you hear them in the Street ?
 Chorus : Glory to God ! don’t you hear them playing,
                        Don t you hear them singing as the Corps goes by ? Glory to God ! what a gladsome sight,
 God bless the Army is my heartfelt cry.

— 13
i9- King of my heart.
               King of the earth and ail Heaven is He Love is His sceptre and truth His decrce Yet in the Soul He will fashion His throne, As king of my heart He reigneth alone.
20.	The Risen Saviour.
               Jésus died, He died to save,
              Conquer sin, and death, and weeping, Burst the shackles of the grave,
              Woke again to know no sleeping.
              Now Mis picrced hands and feet, Bleeding brows and eyes of pity,
               Hosts of prostrate angels greet,
              Welcome Him to Heaven s city.
Bleeding, crying, groaning, dying, ’Twas lor unworthy me.
              Here 1 am Lord, wholly Thine, Lord,
                        1	will live for Thee.
                Jésus lives, he lives to keep,
               Lives to love, support, and strengthen, While I climb life’s rugged steep,
             When the evening shadows lengthen; Nothing can my peace remove,
              Nothing can my joy imprison ;
              Sorrows bathe me in his love,
              Tossings drive me to His bosom.
              Yes, the knock of deàth may come At the dav-break, in the gloaming;
             ’Tis mv Saviours welcome home No more tears, or care, or roaming. Heavenly music greats my car
               l	ills the space around above me, . Harpsand crowns, and victor’s cheer, Christ is altogether lovely.
SOLl VOCAUX Staff Caplani Goldsmith.
2i.	Consolation.
    Chorus : Then ’neath the weight of sorrow’s chain Be this our consolation sjtill :
               It is the Lord that does ordain,
              And bow obedience to His will.]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_07/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_07-0851.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿— 14 —
22.	Confidence.
     Chorus : Lord I will trust thee ail through my life
            Watch o’er and guide me in this world’s strife. Help me to be Lord, loyal and true,
            Until in Heaven Thy face I view.
            SOLI INSTRUMENTAUX
23.	Solo de tambour, Bandsman R. C. Jackson.
   -	, | Adjudant Fuller.
24.	Cornet solo, | ‘Bandsman F.‘Buckman.
25.	Trombone solo, Captain H. IV. ‘Bell.
26.	Euphonium solo, Adjudant Murch.
          CHANTS
       1.	A la croix où mourut mon Sauveur,
  il	Je suis venu brisé de douleur;
  Là son sang purifia mon cœur ;
            A son nom la gloire !
     icr Chœur: A son nom la gloire ! (bis)
                  Là son sang purifia mon cœur,
  A son nom la gloire !
            Quelle merveille ! -— Il vint me sauver ! Quand de sa croix je me fus chargé,
  En moi Jésus vint pour demeurer ;
            A son nom la gloire !
             O	fontaine effaçant le péché,
  Donnant la vie au cœur desséché !
             Là Jésus me retient attaché ;
            A son nom la gloire !
            Pauvre âme, viens aux pieds du Sauveur,
  A la source ouverte à tout pécheur :
             Viens t'y plonger, trouver le bonheur ;
            A son nom la gloire !
     2mc Chœur: A son nom la gloire ! (bis)
                   Viens t’y plonger, trouver le bonheur; A son nom la gloire!
            2.	Tésus, ma force et mon rocher.
           't Mon grand Libérateur,
           Quel ennemi peut m’approcher Sous ton bras protecteur ?

15
     Je veux te bénir à jamais.
    Te louer constamment,
    Et ne m’assurer désormais Que sur ton bras puissant.
Ier Chœur: Nous té bénissons (ter) maintenant Comblés toujours de tes bienfaits, Nous te bénissons maintenant.
    Je t’aimerai de tout mon cœur,
     Je te serai soumis,
    Je rendrai gloire au grand Vainqueur De tous mes ennemis.
    Au temps de mon affliction Tu fus mon ferme appui ;
    Ta sainte bénédiction Me console aujourd’hui.
    De ta puissance environné,
    Mon cœur est ferme en toi ;
    De ton grand salut couronné,
     Je puis tout par la foi,
    Gloire à ton amour précieux,
     Si	doux, si paternel,
    Qui rge prépare un trône aux deux,
    Un royaume éternel !
2me Chœur: Oh ! bénis-moi (ter) maintenant ; Je suis à toi ! tu es à moi !
           Oh ! bénis-moi maintenant !
3.	TVeu nous promet un beau pays,
    1	' Quel bonheur! (bis)
    D’où tous les maux seront bannis,
Quel bonheur ! (bis)
    On entendra le chant des anges,
    Les harpes des saintes phalanges Qui disent de Dieu les louanges,
Quel bonheur ! (bis)
    Ni mort, ni rien de malfaisant N’y viendra (bis) !
    Ni rien de vil, de menaçant N’y viendra ! (bis)
    Nulle âme impure et réprouvée
     Qui refuse d’être lavée
     Par Jésus qui l’aurait sauvée,
N’y viendra ! (bis)]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_07/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_07-0852.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿— i6 —
Pour nous qui sommes des pécheurs, Christ est mort ! (bis)
Par lui Dieu nous rend ses faveurs, Christ est mort ! (bis)
De l’innocence la couronne N’existe plus, mais Dieu nous donne La sainteté quand il pardonne,
Christ est mort ! (bis)
Nous régnerons avec Jésus !
Venez tous ! (bis)
Il	vit, vous serez tous reçus,
Venez tous ! (bis)
La source des eaux vives coule,
O bien-aimés le temps s’écoule !
Le monde sous vos pas s’écroule ! Venez tous ! (bis)
4.	TAés que l’aube dépose
J * Ses perles sur les fleurs,
Dès que s’ouvre la rose Aux brillantes couleurs,
Dès que l’ombre s’efface Devant le jour qui luit, .
A l’œuvre, le temps passe A l’œuvre avant la nuit.
Quand le soleil inonde Et remplit le ciel bleu,
Illuminant le monde De ses rayons de feu.
A l’œuvre sans relâche,
A l’œuvre ! le jour fuit,
    Si	pénible est la tâche Bientôt viendra la nuit.
A cette heure indécise Où le jour disparaît,
   Où murmure la brise A travers la forêt Quand le couchant se.dore Ht que «'éteint le bruit,
Frères, à l’œuvre encore !
Voici, voici la nuit!]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_07/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_07-0853.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿Tournée de la Staff-Musique 1909
Mercredi 19 Jeudi 20 Vendredi 21 21
Samedi 22 22
        99
Dimanche 23 „ 23
23
Lundi 24
24
Mardi 25
25
Mercredi 2(5
26
Jeudi 27 Vendredi 28 Samedi 29 Dimanc he 30 30
Mai
Bâle
Zurich
Constance
Schaffhouse
Winterthour
Saint-Gall
Borschach
Uzwil
Hérisau
Bienne
Cha ux-de-Fonds
La Béroche
Neuchàtel
Lausanne
Genève
Thoune
Berne
Lucerne
Aarau
Zurich
    ifî
Impr. Ed. Beerslecher, Neuveville.]]></page>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>