<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns='http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0'>
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>HEMU Conservatoire de Genève - Programme de concert</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <editionStmt>
        <edition>TEI P5.1 Edition</edition>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>
            <persName>Claudio Bacciagaluppi</persName>
            <persName>Paolo Boschetti</persName>
            <persName>Laurent Pugin</persName>
            <persName>Violeta Struijk van Bergen</persName>
            <persName>Rodolfo Zitellini</persName>
            <date when='2016-01'>Janvier 2016</date>
          </resp>
          <name>Bureau Suisse du RISM</name>
        </respStmt>
      </editionStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>
          <orgName xml:base='http://www.rism-ch.org'>Bureau Suisse du RISM</orgName>
        </publisher>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <idno type='collection'>ch_gc</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>
            <date when='19200403'>03/04/1920</date>
          </title>
          <series>None</series>
          <placeName>Inconnu</placeName>
          <orgName role='holding'>
            Bibliothèque du Conservatoire de Musique de Genève; 
            <link target='http://www.cmusge.ch/contact_bibliotheque'/>
          </orgName>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <!-- all the content of the program in one paragraph -->
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_11/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_11-0897.tif'/>
        <date when='19200403'/>
        <name key='Anonymus' type='person' role='cmp'>Anonymus</name>
        <title/>
        <placeName key='s.l.'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿ u 111111111111111111111111111111111111111111111111111111111111111111111111111111111111111 ■ 1111111111111 n 1111111111111111111111111111111111N11111111M111111111111111111 11 1111111111 m 1111111111111^:
POUNDED
  1918.
The British Music Society.
      (NATIONAL & INTERNATIONAL).
INCORPORATED
1919
  For the furtherance 'of British Musée and Music in Britain. Çpafron - THE RT. HON. A. J. BALFOUR. Çpreeifcenf - THE LORD HOWARD DE WALDEN. ÎEjon. ©irecfor - Dr. A. EAGLEFIELD HULL.
TELEPHONE—REGENT 2481
Vice-Presidents :
  SIR THOMAS BEECHAM.
  SIR FREDERICK BRIDGE, 1J M.V.O.
  General W. S. BRANCKER.
  SIR FREDERIC COWEN.
The Rt Hon. SIR E. E. COOPER
SIR EDWARD ELGAR, O M
SIR HENRY HADOW
SIR ALEXANDER MACKENZIE
SIR WILLIAM McCORMICK
SIR JOHN McCLURE
SIR ERNEST PALMER
SIR CHARLES STANFORD.
THE VERY REV THE DEAN OF CHRIST CHURCH, OXFORD.
SIR HENRY WOOD.
  THE MASTER OF THE MUSICANS’ COMPANY.
General Secretary :
FRANK SOLMAN, ig, Berners Street, W i.
                            19, BERNERS STREET, LONDON, W .1. j* s
Zosr Mr. Held,
rro at*o	te	f-.o .tntO!*»
'ntîrmx rf TO mtî.Tn*' tîio Froaidçnfc mâ Couwil	rt "*• te 'invita
yw tr attend if , ossiblo as t’io Of âwitzerland.
    ■Ï9 mhoiïld /■ortlauloHy 1ÏH to yrtar vlovrr? at tfto varions 'r'	if ym	in
Pr*oncTî v.‘o v?ilï ' yïm ’vi *	V7*flt
y^-nr* T Cfinh©?»*]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_11/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_11-0898.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿ THE BRITISH MUSIC SOCIETY
(INCORPORATED)
~ (NATIONAL AND INTERNATIONAL) ~
Ç(?ûfron : THE RT. HON. A. J. BALFOUR Çfjrestfcenf : THE LORD HOWARD DE WALDEN (PiceîÇpreetienfe :
  SIR THOMAS BEECHAM	SIR JOHN McCLURE
  SIR FREDERICK BRIDGE, M.V.O.	SIR ERNEST PALMER
  GENERAL W. S. BRANCKER	SIR CHARLES STANFORD
SIR FREDERICK COWEN	THE VERY REV. THE DEAN OF CHRIST
  THE RT. HON. SIR E. E. COOPER	CHURCH, OXFORD
  SIR EDWARD ELGAR, O.M.	SIR HENRY WOOD
SIR HENRY HADOW	THE MASTER OF THE MUSICIANS
 SIR ALEXANDER MACKENZIE	COMPANY
  SIR WILLIAM McCORMICK
gon. ©trecfor: DR. A. EAGLEFIELD HULL
%on. JSecrefftrieg for Sotetgn Correcponbence :
MR. E. J. DENT and MR. FRANCIS TOYE
®on. tteaeuret: MR. W. R. DAVIES fjon. âoftctfors: MESSRS. PHILLIPS 6? CUMMINGS «Dfftcee: 19 BERNERS STREET, LONDON, W.l
Commtffee of (glanagcmenf :
  MR ADRIAN C. BOULT	REV. DR. E. H. FELLOWES
  MR. W. W. COBBETT	COL. W. J. GALLOWAY
  MR. ALVIN LANGDON COBURN	MR. H. CART DE LAFONTAINE
  SIR EDWARD E. COOPER	MRS. W. LEE MATHEWS
 MR. W. R. DAVIES	MR. G. BERNARD SHAW
  MR. EDWARD J. DENT	MAJOR E. GEOFFREY TOYE
                   PREAMBLE The British Music Society has been formed to assert at home and abroad the importance of British music of ail periods, and to secure more favorable conditions for the continued production and development of British music of the highest class. The Society enrols not only practising musicians, pro-fessional and amateur, connoisseurs and lovers of music, but ail who are conscious of the national importance of music as an element in culture.]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_11/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_11-0899.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿The Society is not intended to supplant or compete with any existing organization. It has come into existence to do urgently needed work that is now left undone. Music, being a universal art with an universal language, has for two centuries suffered from an excessive concentration of its interests and activities on Italy and Germany. The success with which France and Russia, Poland and Scandinavia, have reacted against this tendency by expressing themselves idiosyncraticallyin music is well known; butEngland stillcountenancesandeven inculcates the superstition that music is a foreign art in which Britons do not excel, and in which, consequently, they would be wise to make a pretenceof not desiring to excel. Some British organization to make known the facts that contradict this barbarous error, and to cultivate the rich musical fertility of our country, can no longer be dispensed with ; and the British Music Society aims at making itself such an organization. The range of its activities will necessarily depend on the support it may receive from the friends of music and of culture ; but the following indications will show howmuch the art of music is dépendent on lay-work which cannot be done by composers and artists for themselves.
THE OBJECTS of the Society are :
(a)	The organization of a propaganda on behalf of British Music, both athome and abroad, by means of:
1.	Leétures and articles in leading newspapers	4. The issue of a monthly Bulletin to record and periodicals at home and abroad.	the progress of British music, and give due noti-
2.	The establishment of a central office in	fïcation of arrangements, &c.
London, where information will be at the dis-	,	r- „ . . , .
posai of British and Continental diredtors, 5; The encouragement of Bndsh interpréta-
artifts, entrepreneursy teachers, and others who	tlve ar ? both vocal and instrumental, to tour
desire information and advice on the subject.	abroad.
3.	The création of branches of the Society in	6. The Annual publication of a Catalogue of thecitiesandtownsofBritainandothercountries.	British Music of permanent interest.
(b)	The fostering of British music by:
I.	Advice and possible aid with publishing 2. The rendering of assistance to orchestral music.	and other performances of British Music.
(c)	The encouragement of the practiçe of music in général and the emphasis
01	its importance in éducation.
(d)	Co-operation with any other Societies having similar objects.
NO UNDUE EMPHASIS will be laid on any particular Musical clique, party, or school of British Music, and the Society will be free from any spécial connexion with or intereft in any firm of publishers or other business organizations.
Ail intereéted in the development of British Music, irrespeétive of sex, âge, profession, or nationality are invited to become MEMBERS—the only qualification being a desire to advance British Music in every possible way.
The Subscriptions are as follows :—
MEMBERS (Full national, international, and local benefits, Monthly Bulletins, Annual and Catalogue, with full voting powers) : One guinea a year, professionals and amateurs alike.
JUNIOR MEMBERS (up to the âge of 21), Full benefits but no voting powers ; Monthly Bulletins, but no Annual and Catalogue: Five Shillings a year.
SCHOOL MEMBERS: Five Shillings a year, One free lecture with grant of Music, books on music, and Bulletins for School Library.
Schools may even adopt Half-a-Crown or smaller subscription, but the total minimum subscription from a School branch must be Seven Guineas a year.
In Centres and Branches there are also:—
ASSOCIATES: Local benefits only, but no voting powers, and no Bulletins: Five Shillings a year.
BULLETIN ASSOCIATES : Half-a-guinea a year. Same advantages as Associates, with addition of the Monthly Bulletins.
Several well-known writers have consented to write Articles on various phases of British Music, and these articles appear in the form of Occasional Paper s, which, together with the monthly Bulletin, are issued gratis to Members, who will further be entitled to receive any advice or information on British Music which they may require.
Members will also be entitled to either free or privileged admission to any Lectures or Concerts arranged by the Society at any Centre or Branch.
The Society is prepared to send out Lecturers (with music illustrations if required) to promote the cause of British Music, old or new.
THE ASSOCIATION is incorporated as an Artiétic Society, not run for profit, under the Companies Consolidation Adt, 1908. The Members’ liability is limited to the amount of One Year’s Subscription.
The Society has the approval of ail the leading British composers and pro-fessional musicians.
For further particulars regarding formation of Centres, Branches, etc., write to the Local Représentative, Local Secretary, or to MR. FRANK SOLMAN, GENERAL SECRETARY, BRITISH MUSIC SOCIETY,
19 Bemers Street, London, W.i
                                    At the Pélican Press, 2 Carmélite Street, E.C.]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_11/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_11-0900.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿]]></page>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>