<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns='http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0'>
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>HEMU Conservatoire de Genève - Programme de concert</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <editionStmt>
        <edition>TEI P5.1 Edition</edition>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>
            <persName>Claudio Bacciagaluppi</persName>
            <persName>Paolo Boschetti</persName>
            <persName>Laurent Pugin</persName>
            <persName>Violeta Struijk van Bergen</persName>
            <persName>Rodolfo Zitellini</persName>
            <date when='2016-01'>Janvier 2016</date>
          </resp>
          <name>Bureau Suisse du RISM</name>
        </respStmt>
      </editionStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>
          <orgName xml:base='http://www.rism-ch.org'>Bureau Suisse du RISM</orgName>
        </publisher>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <idno type='collection'>ch_gc</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>
            <date when='19320412'>12/04/1932</date>
          </title>
          <series>None</series>
          <placeName>Genève, Salle de la Réformation </placeName>
          <orgName role='holding'>
            Bibliothèque du Conservatoire de Musique de Genève; 
            <link target='http://www.cmusge.ch/contact_bibliotheque'/>
          </orgName>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <!-- all the content of the program in one paragraph -->
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_16/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_16-1015.tif'/>
        <date when='19320412'/>
        <name key='Sweelinck, Jan Pieterszoon' type='person' role='cmp'>Sweelinck, Jan Pieterszoon</name>
        <name key='Byrd, William' type='person' role='cmp'>Byrd, William</name>
        <name key='Morley, Thomas' type='person' role='cmp'>Morley, Thomas</name>
        <name key='Gibbons, Orlando' type='person' role='cmp'>Gibbons, Orlando</name>
        <name key='Wilbye, John' type='person' role='cmp'>Wilbye, John</name>
        <name key='Williams, Gerrard' type='person' role='cmp'>Williams, Gerrard</name>
        <name key='Vaughan Williams, Ralph' type='person' role='cmp'>Vaughan Williams, Ralph</name>
        <name key='Janequin, Clément' type='person' role='cmp'>Janequin, Clément</name>
        <name key='Debussy, Claude' type='person' role='cmp'>Debussy, Claude</name>
        <name key='Lasso, Orlando di' type='person' role='cmp'>Lasso, Orlando di</name>
        <name key='Purcell, Henry' type='person' role='cmp'>Purcell, Henry</name>
        <name key='Naylor, E.-W.' type='person' role='cmp'>Naylor, E.-W.</name>
        <name key='Bateson, Thomas' type='person' role='cmp'>Bateson, Thomas</name>
        <name key='Bennet, John' type='person' role='cmp'>Bennett, John</name>
        <name key='Greaves, Thomas' type='person' role='cmp'>Greaves, Thomas</name>
        <title/>
        <placeName key='Genève, Salle de la Réformation '/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿a,-------------^	-------------
SALLE DE LA RÉFORMATION
MARDI .a AVRIL i4.]> A a o HEURES ET DEMIE
“ NOUVELLES AUDITIONS ”
(Saison îç.^i-iç.^a)
CONCERT
tonne par Icj
Flora MANN	N orman STONE
         Nell.e CARSON	Norman NOTLEY
Lilian BERCER	CutkUt KELLY
CA*)
Piano G A VEA U aux soins Je la Manon SA UTIER & JAEGER
-■ r.T.—-	- - , , ■ ■rrrn
BUREAU DM CONCERTS V. ANDRÉOSSI - GENÈVE]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_16/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_16-1016.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿P rogram meJ
 MOTETS
1.	Gaudete Omnes........ J.-P. Sweelinck
Gaudete omnes, et laetamini quia ecce, ecce desideratas venit Introite in conspectu eius in exultateone,
scitote quoniam ipse est expectatio nostra. Alléluia.
2.	Ave Verum............ If'itliam Byrà
Ave verum corpus, natum De Maria Virgine Vere passum, immolatum In cruce pro homine Cujus latus perforatum Unda fluxit sanguine.
Esto nobis prægustatum In mortis examine,
O	dulcis, o pie, o Jesu fili Mariæ miserere mei.
3.	Angélus ad pastores .. J.-P. Sweelinck
Angélus ad pastores ait: „Annuntis vobis
gaudium magnum: quia natus est vobis hodie Salvator mundi. Alléluia.”
-j. Hodie Christus natus est J.-P. Sweelinck
Hodie Christus natus est Noe, Noe,
Hodie Salvator apparuit Alléluia, Alléluia.
Hodie in terra canunt angeli Lætantur archangeli Noe, Noe,
Hodie exultant justi dicentes:
Gloria in excelsis Deo,
Alléluia, Noe.
 MADRIGAUX ET BALLETS
Sing we and chant it. . Thomas Aiorlcy 6. Dainty fine bird....... Orlanào Gibbons
Sing we and chant it. While love doth grant it, Fa la la!
Not long youth lasteth And old âge hasteth,
Now is best leisure,
To take our pleasure.
Fa ta la!
Ail things invite us Now to delight us,
Fa la la!
Hence care be packing, No mirth be lacking,
Let spare no treasure To live in pleasure,
Fa la la!
                                   Dainty fine bird that art encaged there Alas, how like thine and my fortunes are,
                                    Both prisoners be, and both singing thus Strive to please her that hath imprisoned us.
                                   Only thus we differ, thou and I,
                                     Thou liv’st singing, but I sing and die.
                          7. Sweet honey-sucking bees John IFilbyc
                                  Sweet honey-sucking Bees, why do you still Surteit on Roses, Pinks and Violets,
                                    As if the choicest nectar lay in them
                                   Wherewith you store your curious cabinets;
                                   Ah make you flight to Melisuaviæ’s lips;
                                  There may you revel in Ambrosian cheer,
                                    Where smiling Roses and sweet Lilies sit,
                                     Keeping their spring-tide grâces ail the year.
                                    Yet sweet, take heed, ail sweets are hard to get;
                                     Sting not her soft lips, oh beware of that,
                                  For if one flaming dart come from her eye,
                                  Was never dart so sharp, ah then you die!
 CHANSONS POPULAIRES
8.	The Farmer’s Daughters, arr. Gcrrard (Williams
A Farmer he liv’d in the West countrie,
   Bow down, bow down And he had daughters one, two, and three,
Singing I will be true unto my love,
If my love will be true to me.
One day they walk'd by the river's brim,
   Bow down, bow down When the eldest push’d the youngest in, Singing I will be true unto my love,
If my love will be true to me.
”Oh sister, oh sister pray lend me your hand, Bow down, bow down "And l’il give you both house and land. Singing I will be true unto my love,
If my love will be true to me.
u I1- 1J.
”I’ll neither lead you hand nor glove,
   Bow down, bow down ”Unless you promise me your true love Singing I will be true unto my love,
If my love will be true to me.
So down the river the maiden swam,
   Bow down, bow down Until she came to the miller’s dam.
Singing I will be true unto my love,
II my love will be true to me.
The miller’s daughter stood ad the door,
Bow down, bow down Blooming like a gilli-flow’r,
Singing I will be true unto my love,
If my love will be truc to me.
Oh father, oh father, here swims a swan,
   Bow down, bow down ”Very much like a gentle woman.”
Singing I will be true unto my love,
II	my love will be true to me.
The miller he took his rod and hook,
   Bow down, bow down And he fish’d the fair maiden out of the brook, Singing I will be true unto my love,
If my love will be true to me.
9.	The Springtime of the year,
arr. R. Vaughan William*
As I walked out one morning,
In the springtime of the year,
I overheard a sailor boy Likewise a lady fair.
They sang a song together Made the valleys for to ring,
While the birds on spray And the meadows gay Proclaimed the lovely spring.
10.	An acre of land arr. R. Vaughan IP’illianu
My father left me an acre of land,
Ivy sing ivery.
My father left me an acre of land,
And a bunch of green holly and ivery.
P A
CHANSONS
12.	A ce Joly moys de may, Clément Jannequin
A ce joly moys de may,
Faisons tous bonne chère!
Réveillons nous, ne dormons plus;
Dansons ballons et au surplus,
Chascun fasse son essay Pour trouver sa bergère!
A bien danser n’ayons vainscueurs.
Chantons gaiement, soyons vainscueurs!
Celuy de vous le plus gay porte la bannière!
A ce joly moys de may,
Faisons tous bonne chère!
I harrowed it with a bramble bush,
Ivy sing ivery.
I reaped it with a penknife
And a bunch of green holly and ivery.
1 sent it home in a walnut shell,
Ivy sing ivery.
I threshed it with my needle and thread,
And a bunch of green . holly and ivery.
1 winnowed it with my handkerchief,
Ivy sing ivery.
I sent it to mill with a team of great rats,
And a bunch of green holly and ivery.
The carter bought a curly whip,
Ivy sing ivery.
The whip did pop, and the waggon did stop And a bunch of green holly and ivery.
11.	Wassail Song arr. R. Vaugban MPillianu
Wassail, Wassail, ail over the town,
Our bread it is white and our aie it is brown,
Our bowl it is made of the green maple tree.
In the wassail bowl we’ll drink unto thee.
Here’s heateth to the ox and to his right eyc,
Pray God send our master a good Christmas pie,
A good Christmas pie as e’er I did see,
In the wassail bowl we’ll drink unto thee.
Here’s health to the ox and to his right horn,
Pray God send our master a good crop of corn,
A good crop of corn as e’er I did see,
In the wassail bowl we’ll drink unto thee.
Here’s health to the ox and to his long tail,
Pray God send our master a good cask of aie,
A good cask of aie as e’er I did see,
In the wassail bowl we’ll drink unto thee.
Come butler, come fill us a bowl of the best,
Then I pray that your soul in heaven may rest;
But if you do bring us a bowl of the small,
May the devil take butler, bowl and ail!
Then here’s to the maid in the lily-white smock,
Who tripped to the door and slipped back the lock, Who tripped to the door and pulled back the pin For to let these jolly wassailers walk in.
USE
FRANÇAISES
 i3.	Dieu! Qu’il la fait bon regarder, Cl.DebuMy
 Dieu! qu’il la fait bon regarder La gracieuse, bonne et belle.
 Pour les grans biens que sont en elle Chascun est prest de la louer.
 Qui se pourroit d’elle lasser?
 Tousjours sa beauté se renouvelle.
 Dieu! qu’il la fait bon regarder La gracieuse, bonne et belle.
 Par de ça, ne de là, la mer Ne scay dame ne damoiselle Qui soit en tous bien parfais telle,.
 C est ung songe que d i penser. Charles d'ORLÉ&Ns.]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_16/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_16-1017.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿i-f. Quant j’ai ouy le tabourin, Cl. Debuéty
Quant j’ai ouy le tabourin Sonner, pour s’en aller au may,
En mon lit n’en ay fait effray,
Ne levé mon chief du coissin;
En disant, il est trop matin Ung peu je me rendormiray.
Quant j’ai ouy le tabourin Sonner, pour s’en aller au may,
Jeunes gens partent leur butin;
De nonchaloir m’accointeray,
A lui je m’abutineray,
Trouvé l’ay plus prouchain voisin. Charles cI’Orléaws.
DUOS
16.	1 spy Celia............ Henry Purcell
I spy Celia; Celia eyes me.
I approach her; but she flies me.
I pursue; more coy I find her.
1 seem colder; then she’s kinder.
Her eyes charm me; ray words move her,
She esteems me; and I love her.
In not blessing most she blesses,
And not possessing, each possesses.
Now she blushes, I grow bolder.
She would leave me, but I hold her.
She grows angry, I appease her.
I	am redder, then I please her.
17.	John, come kiss me now, arr. E.-IV. Naylor
Wife. John, come kiss me now,
         John, come kiss me by-and-by,
         And make no more ado.
Husband. Peace, I’m angry now,
          Peace, I’m angry at the heart And know not what to do.
          Wives can faine and wives can flatter,
         Hâve I not hit them now.
          When once they begin they still do chatter And so does my wife too.
  j5. Quand mon mari vient de dehors,
Orlando t)i Laaao
  Quand mon mari vient de dehors,
   Ma rente est d’estre battue.
  IL prend la cuiller du pot,
   A la teste me la rue.
  J’ay grand peur qu’il ne me tue.
   C est un faux vilain jaloux.
   C’est un vilain rioteux, grommeleux...
   Je suis jeune, et il est vieux.
 & TRIOS
  Wife. And wives have many fair words and looks, Have I not hit them now,
            And draw silly men on Folly’s hooks.
  Husband. Now of my song I make an end,
             Lo, here I quit thee now,
             Ail evil wives to the devil I send Amongst them my wife too.
  18. The Three Fairies..... Henri/ Purcell
  When the cock begins to crow And the embers leave to glow And the owl cries tu-whit tu-whoo,
  When cricket do sing And mice roam about And midnight bells ring To call the devout,
  When the lazy lie sleeping
  And think it no harm
  Their zeal is so cold
  And their beds are so warm
  When the long lazy slut
  Has not made the parlour clean.
  No water on the hearth is put,
  But ail things in disorder seem;
  Then we trip it round the room And make like bees a drowsy hum,
  Be she Bessy, Nan or Sue,
  We make her of another hue And pinch her black and blue.
MADRIGAUX & BALLETS
19.	Have I found her? ... Tbomai Sale.ion
Have I found her (O rich finding!)
Goddess-like for to behold,
Her fair tresses seemly binding In a chain of pearl and gold ?
Chain me, chain me, O most fair,
Chain me to thee with that hair.
20.	The Silver Swan ..... Orlando Gibbon<1
The Silver Swan who, living, had no note,
When death approached, unlocked her silent throat, Leaning her breast against the reedy shore,
Thus sung her first and last and sung no more. ’Farewell ail joys, O death, come close mine eyes, More geese than swans now live. more fools than wise.”
21.	Lure, Falconers !......... John Bennett
    Hawking for the Héron and Duck.
Lure, falconers! give warning to the field.
Let fly! let fly! make mounting hérons to yield.
Die, fearful ducks, and climb no more so high,
The nyas-hawk will kiss the azuré sky.
But when our soar-hawks fly and stiff winds blow,
Then long too late wc falconers cry ”Hey lo!”
22.	Come away, sweet love ’lhomaa Greavc*
Come away, sweet love, and play thee Lest grief and care betray thee.
Fa la la.
Leave off this sad lamenting,
And take thy heart’s contenting,
The nymphs to sport invite thee,
And running in and out delight thee.
Fa la la.
IMPRIMERIE ORIVET, GENÈVE]]></page>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>