<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?> 
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?> 
<TEI xmlns='http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0'>
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>La Musicale Genève</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <editionStmt>
        <edition>TEI P5.1 Edition</edition>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>
            <persName>Florence Weber</persName>
            <persName>Lynn Beutler</persName>
            <persName>Rodolfo Zitellini</persName>
            <persName>Claudio Bacciagaluppi</persName>
            <persName>Fabienne Grandjean</persName>
            <persName>Sylvain Féjoz</persName>
            <date when='2020-06'>2020</date>
          </resp>
          <name>Bureau Suisse du RISM</name>
        </respStmt>
      </editionStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>
          <orgName xml:base='http://www.rism-ch.org'>Bureau Suisse du RISM</orgName>
        </publisher>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <idno type='collection'>ch_gm</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>
            La Staff-musique internationale de Londres
            <date when='26/05/1909'/>
          </title>
          <series>1908-1909</series>
          <placeName>Genève, Victoria Hall</placeName>
          <orgName role='holding'>
            Bibliothèque du Conservatoire de Musique de Genève; 
            <link target='http://www.cmusge.ch/contact_bibliotheque'/>
          </orgName>
          <idno>BMU VH1 F001083</idno>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Simpson</note>
        <note>Mitchell (dir)</note>
      </notesStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <!-- all the content of the program in one paragraph -->
        <date when='19090526'/>
        <title>La Staff-musique internationale de Londres</title>
        <placeName key='Genève, Victoria Hall'/>
        <name key='1908-1909' type='series'/>
        <name key='Beethoven, Ludwig van' ref='https://muscat.rism.info/admin/people/11035' type='person' role='cmp'>Beethoven, Ludwig van</name>
        <name key='Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus' ref='https://muscat.rism.info/admin/people/115324' type='person' role='cmp'>Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus</name>
        <name key='Meyerbeer, Giacomo' ref='https://muscat.rism.info/admin/people/725' type='person' role='cmp'>Meyerbeer, Giacomo</name>
        <name key='Mendelssohn Bartholdy, Felix' ref='https://muscat.rism.info/admin/people/88790' type='person' role='cmp'>Mendelssohn Bartholdy, Felix</name>
        <name key='Händel, Georg Friedrich' ref='https://muscat.rism.info/admin/people/36552' type='person' role='cmp'>Händel, Georg Friedrich</name>
        <name key='Spohr, Louis' ref='https://muscat.rism.info/admin/people/149499' type='person' role='cmp'>Spohr, Louis</name>
        <name key='Schubert, Franz' ref='https://muscat.rism.info/admin/people/111603' type='person' role='cmp'>Schubert, Franz</name>
        <name key='Haydn, Joseph' ref='https://muscat.rism.info/admin/people/55803' type='person' role='cmp'>Haydn, Joseph</name>
        <name key='Rossini, Gioachino' ref='https://muscat.rism.info/admin/people/63766' type='person' role='cmp'>Rossini, Gioachino</name>
        <name key='Himmel' type='person' role='cmp'>Himmel</name>
        <name key='Simpson' type='person' role='int'>Simpson</name>
        <name key='Mitchell' type='person' role='int'>Mitchell</name>
        <name key='Staff-musique internationale de Londres' type='person' role='int'>Staff-musique internationale de Londres</name>
        <pb facs='CH_Gmu_prg/pyr_bmu_vh1_f001083_001.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[PROGRAMME-RÉPERTOIRE
À SAFF
MUSIQUE
INTERNATIONALE oe LONDRES
SOUS |4 DIRECTION DU
COLONEL SIMPSON
æ æ
Directeur des Réunions :
COMMISSAIRE
W. J. MAC ALONAN
ou
Lieut-Colonel GAUNTLETT
—2
CHERDEFANFARE:
COLONEL MITGIELL
Quartier Général Mational :
BERNE
]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Gmu_prg/pyr_bmu_vh1_f001083_002.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Gmu_prg/pyr_bmu_vh1_f001083_003.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[-Musique
de l'Armée du Salut
Tournée en Suisse du r9 au 31 Mai 1909
| La Fanfare d’Etat-Major de Londres fait actuellement sa troisième
| tournée en Suisse. Les Réunions et les Concerts qu’elle a tenus en
b 1906 et en 1907, ont béni autant que charmé tous ceux qui ont eu le
l privilège d’entendre sa musique, ses chants et ses témoignages, et les
Fanfaristes eux-mêmes en ont été grandement intéressés et réjouis.
Quoique la Staff-Musique ait été sollicitée de visiter d’autres
pays depuis lors, elle revient en Suisse, et c’est la seule campagne
qu'elle puisse faire cette année en dehors de l’Angleterre. Nous som-
\ mes assurés que cette tournée aura autant de succès, si ce n’est davan-
tage, que les années précédentes.
La Staff-Musique se compose de 33 officiers d’Etat-Major, attachés
| au Quartier-Général de l’Armée du Salut à Londres, et qui, en consa-
crant à l'étude le temps de loisir dont ils peuvent disposer, ont acquis
un haut degré de supériorité.
Ces fanfaristes ne sont pas des musiciens de profession, ils em-
ploient leurs dons simplement en vue d’attirer l’attention sur l’Evan-
gile glorieux de Jésus-Christ et se réjouissent d’amener de cette ma-
nière des milliers de personnes à la connaissance du salut.
Cette satisfaction-là est la seule récompense qu’ils reçoivent de
leur œuvre musicale et évangélique ; du reste il en est de même pour
les dix-neuf mille autres musiciens de l’Armiée du Salut. Is ne de-
mandent aucune autre rémunération.
[l ne faut pas oublier que la musique jouée par la Staff-Musique,
si même elle revêt parfois un caractère profane, est cependant pleine
d’un sentiment religieux ; l’Armée, comme on le sait déjà, adapte un
.grand nombre de ses chants à des mélodies qui paraissent s’approprier
au but qu’elle se propose. ;
La musique que la fanfare exécute a été entièrement arrangée et
4 dans bien des cas composée par des salutistes; elle est imprimée dans
les ateliers de l’Armée à Londres où l’on fabrique également les ins-
truments et les uniformes des Fanfaristes.
Nous rappelons encore que le but de la Fanfare est essentiel-
lement évangélique; sa musique contient un message spirituel pour
tous ; une exhortation pour les enfants de Dieu à redoubler d’efforts
à Son service et un message d’avertissement et d’invitation aux in-
convertis.
]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Gmu_prg/pyr_bmu_vh1_f001083_004.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[PROGRAMME-RÉPERTOIRE
________ e &
MARCHES
Les « Marches instrumentales » suivantes, composees par des Salutistes,
ont pour thèmes les pays, les villes ou les sujets mentionnés.
r. France. Introduisant « La Marseillaise ».
2. Germany. Introduisant « La Wacht am Rhein ».
3. Australia. Composée par un Officier attaché au Quartier-Gé-
néral de Melbourne, Australie.
4. New-Zealand. Composée par le Directeur de l’une des fanfa-
res de Christchurch, Nouvelle Zélande
s. The Warrior.
6. The Corret.
7. The Trumpet.
8. The Drum.
9. The Flag.
10. The Proclamation. Composée par le Sous-Chef de fanfare
du corps de Regent-Hall à Londres.
r1. The Great Review.
12. The Standard Bearer.
13. The first-prize March, 1909. Ç0mposu et arrangée par
un jeune fanfariste de l’Armée du Salut à Londres.
14. Good choice. ;
15. Urder tre Colours. Composée par un jeune fanfariste du
corps de Chalk Farm à Londres.
16. The Kettering March. Statf-Captain Goldsmith, de la
7. The Skields March. Composée par le Directeur de la fanfarc.
Staff-Band.
du corps de South Shields, Nord de l’Angleterre.
18: The Tyneside March. ‘
19. The Leyton Mareh. Composée par le Sous-Chef de fanfare
20. The Cadet.
21. Perseverance.
22.
Chicago. Composée par le Directeur de l’une des fanfares de
du corps de Leyton à Londres. i
Chicago, Etats-Unis. ‘
Ÿ
]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Gmu_prg/pyr_bmu_vh1_f001083_005.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[MORCEAUX CHOISIS
Morceaux choisis, hymnes, etc., renfermant des fragments
d'œuvres des grands maîtres et arrangés par le Déparlement Musical de
[;
2
GOSs E D
=
l’Armée du Salut
Selection. a. Beethoven. b. Mozart. c. Meyerbeer. d. Mendel-
sohn.
Selection. a. Händel. b. Spohr. c. Schubert. d. Beethoven.
e. Rossini. f. Haydn.
Hymn. « Supplication » (Beethoven).
Hymn. « The Wondrous Cross » (Himmel).
Hymn. « Oh! Thou who driest the Mourner’s tear » (Haydn).
. March. (Wagner.)
SÉLECTIONS
d’airs nationaux, de mélodies de l’Armée
du Salut et autres
- All Nations. Airs nationaux de 1’Améric1ue, de la Norvège,
des Indes, de la Suède, de la France, de Allemagne, du Ja-
pon, du‘Danemark, de la Hollande, de la Belgique, de la
Grande-Bretagne. L’Armée est actuellement à l’œuvre dans
54 pays différents et prêche l’Evangile en 26 langues.
. International Echoes. Sélection nouvelle des mélodies de
toutes nations.
. Swiss Melodies, Sélection de mélodies populaires suisses,
accueillie avec enthousiasme dans la dernière tournée de la
Staff-Musique en Suisse.
. Songs of Holland. Sélections d’airs nationaux hollandais.
. Jesus lives, Choix de chants au sujet de la mort, du tombeau
et de la résurrection du Sauveur.
a. He lives. b. Christ the Lord is risen to-day. c. Victory
o’er death. d. Jesus lives. e. Up from the grave He arose.
. Songs of Heaven. Chants parlant du ciel et des joies des
rachetés.
a. The Song of Heaven. b. There’s a beautiful land on High.
c. Up in that City paved with Gold. d. Tts true there’s a beau-
tiful City.
- The City of God, Chants parlant des gloires de la Cité céleste.
4. The Beautiful City of Light. b. l have read of a beautiful
City. c. Beautiful Zion. d. Where thé Sun never sets, e. Up in
the golden City. ;
]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Gmu_prg/pyr_bmu_vh1_f001083_006.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[Songs of Joy. Chants parlant du bonheur de ceux qui sui-
vent Christ.
a. Joy, joy, joy. b. He gave me joy. c. Wonderful joy. d. À
Life of joy. e. Joy for to-morrow. f. Sing with joy. —
Hebrew Melodies. Sélection de vieilles mélodies h       
        </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>bÏ.l]k]Uk'.\.
a. The Song of Miniam. W. First‘Fruits. c. The 24 Psalm.-
d. Wailing for the destruction of Jerusalenr. e. Welcome to the
Sabbath. f. The Feast of Lights.
Hebrew Melodies. Sélection de vieilles mélodies hébraïques
employées aux orandes fêtes juives.
a. Leoni. b. God passing Moses. c. The Schofar Call: d. The
Feast of Solemn Assembly. e. The Feast of Trumpets.
Songs of Freedom. Parlant de la liberté de ceux qui ont été
délivrés de l’esclavage du péché.
a. Eree! b: Glory, 'mfree. c. N
dom have I. ;
»1 am free. d. Perfec! Free-
Memories of Childhood. Sélection de chants d'enfants au
sujet de Jésus, du Ciel, dont le plus beau est certainement le
Solo de Cornet. « I think when I read that sweet Story of
Old ». ;
Mercy. Arrangée par Staf-Captain Goldsmith de la Staf-Musique.
a. There 1s Merey in Jesus. b The oreat Physician. cS At
the Cross when a Soul is Pleading. d. Pnr glad m ready.
e. Who’s that knocking at the door.
La finale pathétique donne la description d’uné âme frap-
pant à la porte de la grâce, mais trop tard. Finale. « Knock-
ino, knocking, Then its no use knocking any more. »
Battle Strairs. Arrangé par Staf=Captain Goldsmith de la Stall-
Musique, parle du combat contre le péché, de la victoire et de
la récompense finale du soldat, introduisant :
à Soldier rouse: Thee ! L. The Call to Arms.…h. et c. Battl-
ing for the Lord. d. The Soldier’s Rest. e. Soldiers of the
Mighty One.
My Saviour. a. À never failing Friend. b. My Saviour suffer-
ed on the Tree. c. Thou art a Miohty Saviour.…. d. Oh!,sueh a
Saviour ! e. My Saviour’s still the same.
Peace. a. Perfect peace I enjoy. b. Peace. c. Jesus came with
peacetome ce Rénrecureace- e nipeneer Reaces e m acace
with God.
Songs of Praise. a. Oh! what shall l do my Saviour to praise.
b. Praise Him more and more. c. Now in a Song of grateful
Praise. d. Praise Him for ever. e. Praise God l’m saved. /. Praise
God for what He’s done for me.
Redemption. «. ! an redeemed. Lb. Oh! what a Redeemer.
]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Gmu_prg/pyr_bmu_vh1_f001083_007.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[[9.
The Beautiful Stream. Parle de la source coulant pour
purifier le péché.
a. Oh! have you not heard of the beautiful Stream. b. Come
to this beautiful Stream. c: Still it Aows. d. Oh! come to this
beautiful Stream.
Songs of Comfort. a. Come ye disconsolate. b. Don’t forget
He’s near thee. c. I will guide thec. d. He wipes the tear from
\f;1'}‘ eve.
Echoes from Caivary. Parlant-des souffrances, de la mort,
du tombeau et de la résurrection du Ï‘Ë‘\‘îj_“llclll Jésus-Christ.
a. Gethsemane. L. When I s survey. c. At Calvary. d: At-the
Tomb of our Lord. e. The Resurrection ;
Guide me oh Thou Great Jehovah.u. Guide me. b. The
Verge of Jorden. c. The Crystal ]‘HllLlill
Prircethorpe. Arrangé par le Major Ostby, de la Suède. Ré-
flexion sur les expériences p……\ de l’âme, ét ses espérances
glorieuses.
a. Meditation. b. Praises to our King. c. Dark and ever
darker was the wintry past. d. (Lnu still, and ever clearer,
dawns the lioht from Heaven . Higher then, and higher, bear
the ransomed Soul.
Songs of Heaven. a. Roll Jordan, roll. b. And \"l1uu [ reach
those pearly Gates. c. There is a City bright. d. Meeting in
Heaven. e. When the Roll is called up yonder. f. I\I} beautiful
Home.
International Echoes. a.‘Danemark, To war for God. b. Ca-
nada, The one I love. c. 81/…/z. The pr…«…\ Fountain. d. Etats-
Unis, Ex erybody has a work to do. e. Norvège, March on.
HYMNES, etc.
Jerusalem, My happy Home.
Jerusalem. mv happy Home,
Name ever dear to me :
When shall my labours have an end ?
In Joy and Peac& with Thee ?
Oh, when, thou C ity of my God,
Shall l thy courts 4su…l
Where congregations ne’er break up,
And Sabbaths have no end ?
There happier bow’rs than Eden’s bloom.
No sin nor sorrow know :
Blest Seat! th t»ng]l rude and stôrmy scenes,
I onward press to you.
]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Gmu_prg/pyr_bmu_vh1_f001083_008.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[6.
se 0
Jerusalem ! Jerusalem !
Name ever dear to me!
Why should ! shrink at pam or woe ?
Or feel at death dismay ?
l’ve Canaan’s goodly land in view,
And realms of endless day.
Jerusalem ! my happy Home!
My soul still pants for thee ;
Then shall my labours have an end,
When I th3 joys shall see.
Jerusalem ! Jerusalem !
Name ever dear to me !
Name ever dear to me!
. Before Jehovah’s awful Throne.
Before Jehovah’s awful Throne
Ye nations bow with sacred joy.
Wher I survey the wondrous cross. (Wareham.)
When I survey the wondrous cross
On which the Prince of Glory died
My richest gain I count but loss,
‘And pour contempt on all my pride.
. Take my life and let it be. (Nottingham.)
lake my life, and let it be
Consecrated, Lord to Thee,
Take my moments and my days,
Let then flow in ceaseless praise.
. Rock of Ages cleft for me. (Rousseau.)
Rock of Ages cleft for me
Let me hide myself in Thee
Let the Water and the Blood
From Thy wounded side which flowed
Be of sin the double cure
Save from wrath and make me pure.
Jdesus Lover of my Soul.
Jesus Lover of my soul
Let me to Thy bosom fly,
While the nearer Waters roll
While the Tempest still is hwh
Hide me, oh my Saviour hide
Till the storm of Life be past
Safe into the Haven guide
Oh! receive my boul at last.
. Lead kindly Light.
(Voir Musique vocale, N° 10 Quartette.)
]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Gmu_prg/pyr_bmu_vh1_f001083_009.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[— 7 —
MUSIQUE VOCALE
CHŒURS DES FANFARISTES AVEC ACCOMPAGNEMENT
D'INSTRUMENTS
1. Who with me will a soldier be ?
Who with me will a Soldier be,
In the Army which the Lord delights to bless ?
With the cross before we will march to war
In the cause of freedom and righteousness.
2. Nazareth. (Gounod.)
Jesus, loved redeemer, unto us impart
Lowliness of spirit, righteousness of heart.
CHŒURS DES FANFARISTES
3. The Soldier’s Chorus. (Gounod.)
AIl Praise and Glory to God on high,
Who gave the Saviour for us to die ;
Now we are fully redeemed from sin,
And ready to fight or ready to die men’s souls to win.
2
Sin is mighty and strong, and who can be free ?
See how eager the throng for sin’s gaiety !
Thanks be unto our God, He has made a way,
By giving His Son, He victory has won,
And now we can say —
Oh! what wondrous love the Saviour has for ev'ry guilty, helpless sinner,
Rest and peace he offers free to all who from their sins will turn away ;
Able now to save and break the bonds that strong have been your
He cannot fail, but shall prevail, [soul to hinder,
His mighty power can libérate the fetter’d soul from sin to-day ;
He cannot fail, but shall prevail,
His mighty power can liberate the fetter’d soul from sin to-day.
OCTFIIERS VOCANU
Staf} Captain Reardon \ st'Tann  “Brigadier Hurren 15e à
Lieut.-Col. Le Bult |"  Tenoi Bandsman Greenwood | " Bass
Adjudant Fuller Staf Capt.Hammertony _ Bass
Bandsman Buckman Staf} Capt. Goldsmith | A r
4. Glad Times.
Tell it abroad, Good is the Lord,
Let us be glad, let us rejoice
Singing with heart and voice,
For He is worthy dominion to receive.
} 2»d'Tenor
]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Gmu_prg/pyr_bmu_vh1_f001083_010.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[Praise ye the Lord.
Praise ye the Lord ! Praise the Lord À
He’s worthy to be praiscd ;
So raise your voice in cheertul song today. %
Raise your voice in cheerful song,
Praise, praise, praise, praise !
He is our God, the mighty King of Kings,
At whose br1ght presence d1rkness flies awa ay-
Praise ye the Lord ! Praise ye the Lord !
Remember me.
When storms around are sweeping, > . E
When lone my watch l’m keeping, ;
"Mid fires of evil tallmg,
"Mid tempters voices calling,
Remember me, O Mighty One. (repeal.)
When walking on life’s ocean,
Control its mginU motion ;
When from its dangers shnnlung,
When in its dread deep> sinking,
Remember me, O Mighty One. (repeat.)
When weight of sin oppresses,
When dark despair distresses,
AIl thro’ the Life that’s mortal,
And when I pass death’s portal,
Remember me, O Mighty One. (repeal.)
March on.
We find delioht in fighting for Jesus,
Grand is the \ ar îor our lhdcunu !
Our foes may threaten. but love’s glorious flame
Burns within our hearts for him.
Forward go ! Forward go ! March on !
Love to (;0d makes us go to fight, ; |
Glory soon will be given. . ‘
In the land where 1hc_\ walk in white, #
Endless peace is in Heaven.
We stand for truth and righteousness,
For God we shed our blood,
We”re passing through this earth’s distress ;
To rest and peace with God.
We’ll sing for ever of this love,
And of the grace we daily prove,
That helps us in the fight to win. |
O Soldier of the living God, |
March on! ‘
]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Gmu_prg/pyr_bmu_vh1_f001083_011.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[RE RERE p ! N
es
T
rrs
F à
r r p r r A A
P es 173720
e E TPE
4 D5 sr = GH rrn dn €
-8. Onward March.
Onward, onward, march to victory !
Though the foe be very near, yet our hearts have not a fear.
We will march, and the song of victory sing,
For we battle for the right,
Leaning on our 5auo… s might,
s© H1s banner we will çl11w, Jl]d boldly sing,
Onward, on we march to (;lon !
With our banners flying, Hn<ï everywhere ;
We're marching onw md onw ard now to G lm\ !
Hark the 501ws !
Hark the songs of \lk.t()l\ swelling o’er the battlefield !
And when thls life is o’er and victry won,
We’ll up to Glory go, our hearts made w hltç as snow,
For Jesus died that we to Heaven might go,
And be for ever there with the Holy ones.
9. The Army Drum.
One day a band of Army Soldiers
Were Sounding aloud their drum, drum, drum, drum,
Âs through the bt1utx they marched along
And f11 above the sound of song
The noisy drum said come — (répéler 8 Jois)
The noisy drum said (mnc'
9*. Negro Plantation Song. « Who built the Ark. »
QUATUORS VOCEAUX
Staf} Caplain Reardon. Lieut.-Col. Le Bult. Brigadier Hurren.
Slaf} Captain Goldsmiüth.
10. Lead kindly Light.
Lead kindly Light, amidst the encircling gloom,
Lead Thou me on!
The night is dark. and | am far from Home
Lead Thou me on!
Keep Thou my feet ; I do not ask to see
The distant scene : one step enough for me.
[ was not ever thus, nor prayed that Thou,
Should’st lead me on :
I lov’d to choose and see my path; but now,
Lead Thou me on !
[ lov’d the garish day ; and, spite of fears,
Pride rul’d my will, rununbm not past years,
]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Gmu_prg/pyr_bmu_vh1_f001083_012.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[TO —
So long Thy pow’r hast blest me, sure it still
Will lead me on.
O’er moor and mountain, crag and torrent, till
The night is gone,
And with the morn, those angel faces smile,
Which I have lov'd long since, and lost awhile.
Providence.
Oh! how entraining life’s prospect seemed
As on its s*pri1wtimc the Sun brighthy beamed
The song 0t the birds to my heart secmcd to say
Have ne’er a fear. ’twill be thus on the w ay.
False was the message I learned, oh! so soon,
For shadows had gathered and deepened e’er noon
And but for the guidance from Heaven bestowed,
I should have wandered far off the road.
Chorus:  Too wise to err, too good to be unkind
My Saviour lp1d\ I follow close behind
Whate ’er befalleth PIl trust Him to the end
Heaven’s chiefest glory, earth’s dearest friend.
DUOS VOCAUX
Brigadier Hurren. Staf} Captain Reardon.
We are happy, glad and free.
We are happy, glad and free,
We were blind but now we see,
Now our hearts are full of joy,
And new songs our lips employ ;
Jesus has given hb…\
Sinner, HL ll do the same for thee.
To heal the broken heart.
A Hiding-place from every storm,
À shelter that defends from harm,
À light that cheers the path of 0100m
Is Christ to all who to Him come,
O wounded hcaxt thy sorrow brine,
For thou may'st gain relief from Him
Who gave His l1fg so to redeem
Each grieving soul o’erthrown by sin.
To heal the broken heart he came,
To free the captive from his chain,
The Blood He spilt when He was slain
Brings guilty sinners home to God.
]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Gmu_prg/pyr_bmu_vh1_f001083_013.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[A
SPFET TS E A PE
Ss E
O trembling, thy heavy weight
Of guilt just now to Jesus take,
He shed His blood that He might make
À cleansing fountain for thy sake.
Thy bonds shall break, O captive one,
For Christ to set thee free has come,
He waits to give the precious boon,
The freedom thou hast sought so long.
14. As well.
Now in a song of grateful praise
To my dear Lord will I raise
With all His Saints l’Il join to tell
My Jesus hath done all things well.
SOLI VOCAUX. — Staff Captain Reardon.
IS. À plea for pardon.
Guilty, guilty,
Nothing have I to bring,
Nothing to gain Thy Grace Lord,
Nothing but a life of sin ;
Grieving, mourning,
Over a wasted past,
Here dear Saviour,
Myself at Thy feet I cast.
In Thy heart there’s Mercy, in Thy love there’s hope
Thou wilt raise the fallen, Thou wilt lift me up,
Guilty helpless, l to Thine arms now fly
Save, olh save me, a sinner condemned to die.
Trembling, hoping,
Flying from dark despair,
Have I not heard that Thou, Lord
Heedeth the sinner’s prayer ?
Groaning, bleeding,
Dying on Calvary,
There Thou purchased
Salvation and Life for me.
Love so boundless,
Henceforth my all shall claim,
Bought by Thy Blood so precious.
Saved by Thy grief and pain ;
I can ne’er, Lord,
Pay Thee the debt ! owe,
But my life, Lord,
In service for Thee shall flow.
]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Gmu_prg/pyr_bmu_vh1_f001083_014.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[Calvary.
O (…11\ ary ! o Caivary ! the thorn, the erown. the spear.
Tis there thy love, my Jesus, in flowing wounds 1} p…1
O depths of love and mercy, to those dear wounds I f
I was a guilty sinner, but Jesus died for me.
17. The Sufferings of Jesus.
Whenc'er I stop to ponder
O” er the story of the Cross,
My soul is filled whith wonder,
And in amazement lost;
To think that Christ for such as me
Gave up His life on Calvary,
That I from sin might be set free
He there for me was slain.
For me my Lord was slain,
For me he suffered pain,
He bled and died, was crucified,
‘That 1 might pardon gain ;
For me my Lord was s1- ain,
For me He bore the shame,
”Twas for my guilt His blood was spilt.
Oh! Glory to His name !
[ see Him in the Garden,
And I hear the prayer He prayed
When sin, the world’s great burden,
Upon the Lord was laid,
« Oh, let this cup pass now from Me, »
He cries in bitter agony.
« Yet not My will, but Thine to be, »
With God the Saviour pleads.
18. The Veteran.
Just wheel my chair to the window
And wide the casement fling,
For I want to see the Army
As they march along and s sing,
So fetch me my old red guernsey
And set me upon my feet
For The Army Band 1s comine;
Don’t you hear them in the street ?
Chorus : Glory to God ! don’t you hear them playing,
Don’t you hear them singing as the Corps goes by ?
Glory to God ! what a gladsome sight,
God bless the Army is my heartfelt cry.
]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Gmu_prg/pyr_bmu_vh1_f001083_015.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[#
p
e
Ct apnt
T r r d
e EME E e C en à
19. King of my heart.
King of the earth and all Heaven is He
Love is His sceptre and truth His decree
Yet in the Soul He will fashion His throne.
As king of my heart He reigneth alone.
20. The Risen Saviour.
Jesus died, He died to save,
Conquer sin, and death, and w ecping,
3urst the shackles of the grave,
Woke again to know no \I…p…ﬂ.
Now His pierced hands and feet,
Bleeding brows and eves <wîd pity,
Hosts of prostrate angels greet,
Welcome Him to Heaven’s city.
hlud…<v. crying, groaning, dying,
I\. às for unworthy me.
Here | am Lord, wholly Thine, Lord,
[ will live for Thee.
Jesus lives, he lives to keep,
Lives to love, support, and strengthen,
While I climb life’s rugged steep,
When the evening shadows lengthen ;
\tvtliing can my peace remove,
Nothing can my joy imprison ;
Sorrows bathe me in his love,
Tossings drive mé to His bosom.
Yes, the knock of death mav come
Ât the dav-break, in-the …]………….
SISI my Saviours \ul…mu home
No more tears, or care. or roaming.
Heavenly music greats my car
Fills the space around above me,
Harps and crowns, and victor’s cheer,
Christ is altogether lovely.
SOLI VOCAUX
Slaf} Caplain Goldsmith.
21. Consolation.
Chorus : Then ’neath the weight of sorrow’s chain
Be this our consolation still
It 1s the Lord that does ordain,
\nd bow obedience to His will.
]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Gmu_prg/pyr_bmu_vh1_f001083_016.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[22.
23.
24.
d
26.
= I4 —-
Confidence. ;
Chorus : Lord I will trust thee all through my life
Watch o’er and guide me in this world’s strife.
Help me to be Lord, loyal and true,
Until in Heaven Thy face I view.
SOLI INSTRUMENTAUX
Solo de tambour, Bandsman R. C. Jackson.
c | Adjudant Fuller.
ornet SOlO,‘ Bandsman F. Buckman.
Trombone solo, Caplain H. W. Bell.
Euphonium solo, Adjudant Murch..
CHANTS
Té la croix où mourut mon Sauveur,
Je suis venu brisé de douleur ;
Là son sang purifia mon cœur ;
A son nom la gloire !
rer Chœur: À son nom la gloire ! (bis)
Là son sang purifia mon cœur,
A son nom la gloire !
Quelle merveille ! — Il vint me sauver !
Quand de sa croix je me fus chargé,
En moi Jésus vint pour demeurer ;
À son nom la gloire !
O fontaine effaçant le péché,
Donnant la vie au cœur desséché !
Là Jésus me retient attaché ;
À son nom la gloire !
Pauvre âme, viens aux pieds du Sauveur,
À la source ouverte à tout pécheur :
Viens t’y plonger, trouver le bonheur ;
ÀA son nom la gloire !
2me Chœur: À son nom la gloire ! (bis)
Viens t’y plonger, trouver le bonheur ;
À son nom la gloire!
2R ]ésus, ma force et mon rocher.
#  Mon grand Libérateur,
Quel ennemi peut m’approcher
Sous ton bras protecteur ?
f
q
]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Gmu_prg/pyr_bmu_vh1_f001083_017.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[Je veux te bénir à jamais,
Te louer constamment,
Et ne m’assurer désormais
Que sur ton bras puissant.
D e e
Î
1°* Chœur: Nous te bénissons (fer) maintenant ;
Comblés toujours de tes bienfaits,
Nous te bénissons maintenant.
P R IS CON
E EN OE r rr
QR
Je t’aimerai de tout mon cœur,
Je te serai soumis,
Je rendrai gloire au grand Vainqueur
De tous mes ennemis.
Au temps de mon affliction
Tu fus mon ferme appui ;
Ta sainte bénédiction
Me console aujourd’hui.
RE RE
De ta puissance environné,
Mon cœur est ferme en toi ;
De ton grand salut couronné,
Je puis tout par la foi,
Gloire à ton amour précieux,
Si doux, si paternel,
Qui me prépare un trône aux cieux,
Un royaume éternel !
rr e
_
R F EN E PE A
2me Chœur: Oh ! bénis-moi (Zer) maintenant ;
Je suis à toi! tu es à moi !
Oh ! bénis-moi maintenant !
2 ] ieu nous-promet un beau pays,
Quel bonheur! (bis)
D’où tous les maux seront bannis,
Quel bonheur ! (bis)
On entendra le chant des anges,
Les harpes des saintes phalanges
Qui disent de Dieu les louanges,
Quel bonheur ! (bis)
D As
Ni mort, ni rien de malfaisant
N’y viendra (bis)!
Ni rien de vil, de menaçant
N’y viendra ! (bis)
Nulle âme impure et réprouvée
Qui refuse d’être lavée
Par Jésus qui l'aurait sauvée,
N’y viendra ! (bis)
|
;
PE n
]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Gmu_prg/pyr_bmu_vh1_f001083_018.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[m
Pour nous qui sommes des pécheurs,
Christ est mort ! (bis)
Par lui Dieu nous rend ses faveurs,
Christ est mort ! (bis)
De l’innocence la couronne
N’existe plus, mais Dieu nous donne
La sainteté quand il pardonne,
Christ est mort ! (bis)
Nous règnerons avec Jésus !
Venez tous ! (bis)
Il vit, vous serez tous recus,
Venez tous! (bis)
La source des eaux vives coule,
O bien-aimés le temps s’écoule !
Le monde sous vos pas s’écroule !
Venez tous ! (bis)
4. ])C> que l’aube dépose
ë Ses perles sur les fleurs,
Dès que s’ouvre la rose
Aux brillantes couleurs,
Dès que l’ombre s’efface
Devant le jour qui luit,
À l’œuvre, le temps passe
À l’œuvre avant la nuit.
Quand le soleil inonde
Et remplit le ciel bleu,
Illuminant le monde
De ses rayons de feu.
À l’œuvre sans relâche,
À l’œuvre ! le jour fuit,
Si pénible est la tâche
Bientôt viendra la nuit.
À cette heure indécise
Où le jour disparait,
Où murmure la brise
À travers la forêt
Quand le couchant se dore
Et que s’éteint le bruit,
Frères, à l’œuvre encore !
Voici, voici la nuit!
NS E
IN
]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Gmu_prg/pyr_bmu_vh1_f001083_019.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Gmu_prg/pyr_bmu_vh1_f001083_020.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[Mercredi 19 Mai .
Jeudi 20
Vendredi 21 .
E D
Samedr "
2
,
Dimanche 23
25
99
° ZO
Lundi 24
* 24
Mardi D5
* 25
Mercredi 26 .
= 20
Jeudi uT
Vendredi 28 ,,
Ssamedu 23
Dimanche 30
30
,,
Tournée de la Staff-Musique
1909
Bâle
Zurich
Constance
Schaffhouse
Winterthour
Saint-Gall
Rorschach
Uzwil
Hérisau
Bienne
Chaux-de-Fonds
La Béroche
Neuchâtel
[Lausanne
Genève
Thoune
Berne
Lucerne
Aarau
Zurich
Impr. Ed. Beerstecher, Neuveville.
]]></page>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>