<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?> 
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?> 
<TEI xmlns='http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0'>
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Freunde alter Musik Basel</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <editionStmt>
        <edition>TEI P5.1 Edition</edition>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>
            <persName>Claudio Bacciagaluppi</persName>
            <persName>Laurent Pugin</persName>
            <persName>Rodolfo Zitellini</persName>
            <date when='2016-01'>Janvier 2016</date>
          </resp>
          <name>Bureau Suisse du RISM</name>
        </respStmt>
      </editionStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>
          <orgName xml:base='http://www.rism-ch.org'>Bureau Suisse du RISM</orgName>
        </publisher>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <idno type='collection'>ch_famb</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>
             Concert 
            <date when='19871202'>02/12/1987</date>
          </title>
          <series>Konzerte</series>
          <placeName>Basel, Martinskirche</placeName>
          <orgName role='holding'>
             Archiv des Vereins Freunde alter Musik Basel; 
            <link target='http://famb.ch/'/>
          </orgName>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <!-- all the content of the program in one paragraph -->
        <pb facs='CH_Bm_prg/pyr_CH_Bm_prg-1404.tif'/>
        <date when='19871202'/>
        <name key='Schütz, Heinrich' type='person' role='cmp'>Schütz, Heinrich</name>
        <name key='Monteverdi, Claudio' type='person' role='cmp'>Monteverdi, Claudio</name>
        <name key='Ward, John' type='person' role='cmp'>Ward, John</name>
        <name key='Lawes, Henry' type='person' role='cmp'>Lawes, Henry</name>
        <name key='Lawes, William' type='person' role='cmp'>Lawes, William</name>
        <name key='Le Blanc, Suzie' type='person' role='int'>Le Blanc, Suzie</name>
        <name key='Tubb, Evelyn' type='person' role='int'>Tubb, Evelyn</name>
        <name key='Nichols, Mary' type='person' role='int'>Nichols, Mary</name>
        <name key='King, Andrew' type='person' role='int'>King, Andrew</name>
        <name key='Müller, Rufus' type='person' role='int'>Müller, Rufus</name>
        <name key='Ewing, Alan' type='person' role='int'>Ewing, Alan</name>
        <name key='Rooley, Anthony' type='person' role='int'>Rooley, Anthony</name>
        <title>Konzerte</title>
        <placeName key='Basel, Martinskirche'/>
        <name key='Konzerte' type='series'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿Freunde Alter Musik ln Basel
1.	Konzert
Mittwoch, 2. Dezember 1987, 20.15 Uhr in der Martinskirche
Donnerstag, 3. Dezember 1987, 20.00 Uhr Augustinermuseum Freiburg im Breisgau
]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Bm_prg/pyr_CH_Bm_prg-1405.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿The Consort of Mus icke London
Leitung: Anthony Rooley
Sopran:	Suzie le Blanc, Evelyn Tubb
Alt:	Mary Nichols
Tenor:	Andrew King, Rufus Müller
Bass:	Alan Ewing
                             Hinweis
Das zweite Konzert der "Freunde alter Musik Zusammenarbeit mit dem Fortepiano-Symposium Basiliensis am Donnerstag, 14. Januar 1988, des Stadtcasinos Basel statt.
"Die späte Kammermusik Carl Philipp Emanuel
Wilbert Hazelzet (Flöte), Hajo Bäss (Viola) , piano)
in Basel" findet in der Schola Cantorum
20.15	Uhr im Festsaal
Bachs"
Andreas Staier (Forte

Das virtuose Madrigal
Schutz, Monteverdi, Ward und Lawes
Selve Beate Alma afflitta
Heinrich Schütz
0 cone sei gentile
Claudio Monteverdi
Dunque addio
Vorrei baciarti
Heinrich Schütz
Claudio Monteverdi
Ride la primavera
Heinrich Schütz
0 sia tranquillo il mare
Claudio Monteverdi
Feritevi, ferite
Heinrich Schütz
Pause
No object dearer
John Ward
This mossy bank
Down in a dale Cruel unkind
Henry Lawes John Ward
 I laid me down Amintor's Welladay
Henry Lawes
If heaven's just wrath
John Ward
Awake, fair Floramell When death shall snatch us
Henry Lawes William Lawes
If the deep sighs
John Ward]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Bm_prg/pyr_CH_Bm_prg-1406.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿Teil 1
SELVE BEATE Selve beate,
Se sospirando in flebili susurri Al nostro lamentar vi lamentaste, Gioite anco al gioire, e tante lingue Sciogliete quante frondi Scherzano al suon di queste piene del gioir nostro aure ridenti.
ALMA AFFLITTA
Alma afflitta, che fai?
Chi ti darh piü vita,
Se colei, per cui vivi, oggi £ partita? Ahi, son ben folle e cieco,
Con l'alma a ragionar che non & meco.
0 COME SEI GENTILE
O	come sei gentile
Caro augellino; o quanto
E’l mio stato amoroso al tuo simile:
Io	prigion, tu prigion;
Tu canti, io canto.
tu canti per colei
Che t’ha legato et io canto per lei.
Ma in questo 6 differnti La mia sorte dolente:
Che giova pur a te l'esser canoto; Vivi cantando et io cantando moro.
DUNQUE ADDIO
Dunque addio, care selve, care mie selve addio.
Ricevete questi Ultimi sospiri,
finchä sciolta da ferro ingiusto e crudo
torni la mia fredd’ombra
alle vostr'ombre amate,
che nel penoso inferno
non puö gir innocente,
ne puö star tra beati
disperata e dolente.
Schütz / Guarini
 !>
Schütz / Marino
Monteverdi / Guarini
Schütz / Guarini]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Bm_prg/pyr_CH_Bm_prg-1407.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿ VORREI BACIARTI
Vorrei baciarti, O Filii,	Monteverdi
Ma non so come ove'1 mio bacio scocchi.
Ne la bocca o negl'occhi.
Cedan le labra a voi, lumi divini,
Fidi specchi del core,
Vive stelle d'Amore!
Ah, pur mi volgo a voi, perle e rubini,
Tesoro di bellezza,
Fontana di dolcezza,
Bocca, onor del bei viso:
Nasce il pianto da lor, tu m'apri il riso!
RIDE LA PRIMAVERA
Ride la primavera,	Schütz
torna la bella Clori,
odi la rondinella,
mira 1'herbette e i fiori.
Ma tu Clori piü bella, nella stagion novella.
Serbi l'antico verno, deh, s'hai cinto il cor di ghiaccio eterno.
Perche, ninfa crudel, quanto gentile, porti negl'occhi il sol, nel volt'aprile?
O	SIA TRANQUILLO IL MARE	Monteverdi
0	sia tranquillo il mare, o pien d'orgogli,
Mai da quest'ondi io non rivolgo il piede,
10	qui t'aspetto e qui de la tua fede,
Tradito amante, mi lamento e doglio.
Spesso salir su queste rupi io soglio Per veder se il tuo legno ancor se riede Quivi m'assido e piango, onde mi crede
11	mar un fonte, el navigante un scoglio,
E spesso ancor t'invio, per messagieri,
A vidir la mia pena e'l mio tormento,
Dell'aria vaga i zeffiri leggiero.
Ma tu non torni, o Filii, e'l mio lamento
L'aura disperge e tal merce ne speri
Chi fida a Donna il cor e i prieghi al vento.
FERITEVI, FERITE
Feritevi, ferite, viperette modaci	Schütz
dolci guerriere ardite
del dilett'e d'amor bocchi sagaci,
saettatevi pur'vibrat'ardenti,
l'armi vostre pungenti,
ma le morti sien vite,
ma le guerre sien paci,
sien saette le lingue,
e piagh'i baci.

Teil 2
NO OBJECT DEARER
No object dearer, nor no love, so crossed;	John Ward
If ever good cause suffered under might,
If ever joys were checked in proudest boast,
Or ever Claim did nonsuite kingdom's right,
Our love, our joy, our right and all are lost.
Time, death and nature, armed by fate's despite,
By this one fatal blow so deadly given Doth make us groan under the wrath of heaven.
THIS MOSSY BANK
(A dialogue between a Shepherd and Nymph) Shepherd: This mossy bank they pressed.
Henry Lawes
Nymph:
Chorus:
Shepherd:
Nymph:
Shepherd:
Nymph: Shepherd:
Chorus:
Nymph: Shepherd:
Nymph:
Shepherd: Nymph: Shepherd: Nymph: Shepherd: Nymph:
That aged oak did canopy the happy pair All night from the dark air.
Here let us sit and sing the -words they spoke, When the day breaking their embraces broke.
See, love, the blushes of the morn appear,
And now she hangs her pearly störe Robb'd from the Bastern shore, i'th' Cowslips-bell and Roses ear:
Sweet, I must stay no longer here.
Those streaks of doubtful light usher not day, No morn shall shine tili thy return;
The yellow planet and the grey Dawn shall attend thee on the way.
If thine eyes gild my their useless shine.
                      paths, they may forbear
My tears will quite extinguish their faint light.
Those drops will make their beams more clear:
Love's flames will shine on ev'ry tear.
They wept and kissed, and from their lips and
eyes in a mixt dew of briny sweet
Their joys ans sorrows meet: but she cries out:
Shepherd arise, the sun betrays us eise to spies.
The winged hours fly fast whilst we embrace;
But when we want their help to meet,
They move with leaden feet.
Then let us pinion Time, and Chase the day For ever from this place.
Hark!
Ah me! Stay.
For ever.
No, no, arise, we must be gone.
My nest of spiee.
My soul.]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Bm_prg/pyr_CH_Bm_prg-1408.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿Shepherd: My paradise.
Chorus. Neither could say farewell, but through their eyes Grief interrupted speech, with tears supplies.
DOWN IN A DALE	Ward
Down in a dale sat a nymph weeping,
A lovely swain lay by her sleeping;
She jogged and jogged to have him wake.
He hunched and punched and no think spake,
She gave him twenty and twenty kisses,
Beside her sighs and amorous wishes Till echo from her plaints did chide him Which made him shake and run to hide him In a pleasant thicket by.
After him the nymph did hye
And for his churlishness before
He pleased her so she cried no more.
CRUEL UNKIND
Cruel unkind, oh stay thy flying.	Ward
Least with thy flight thou cause my dying;
Pity the wretch that for thy love doth languish,
With cruel pain and undeserved anguish.
I	LAID ME DOWN
I	laid me down upon a pillow soft,	Henry Lawes
And dreamed I clipped and kissed my mistress oft:
She cried, Fie fie, away, you are too bold.
I	prayed her be content, though she were cold,
My veins did burn with. flames of hot desire,
And must not leave tili she had quenched my fire.
Well, since (said she) I may not from you fly,
Do what you please, I give you liberty.
With that I waked, but found I was deceived;
For which I stormed like one of sense bereaved.
AMINTOR'S WELLADAY
Chloris now thou art fled away,	Henry Lawes
Amintor's sheep are gon astray;
And all the joy he took to see His pretty lambs run after thee Is gon, is gon, and he alone,
   Sings nothing now but welladay, welladay.
His oaten pipe that in thy praise Was wont to play such roundelays,
Is thrown away, and not a swain Dares pipe, or sing, within his plain;
   ’Tis death for any now to say One word to him but welladay.

The maypole where thy little feet So roundly did in measures meet,
Is broken down, and no content Comes near Amintor since you went. All that I ever hear him say Was Chloris, Chloris, welladay.
Upon those banks you us'd to tread He ever since hath laid his head,
And whisper'd there such pining woe, As not a blade of grass will grow;
O Chloris! Chloris! come away,
And hear Amintor’s welladay.
IF HEAVEN'S JUST WRATH
If heaven's just wrath may move an earthly man	Ward
For virtues loss let each heart give a groan,
With tears and sighs in grief's sharp bitter anguish,
Let truth express true plaints, let all hearts languish. While he's gone up to sing heaven's highest praise,
Let us below bewail in mournful lays;
With varying tunes fall flat before his grace,
And pray such goodness long succeed his place.
AWAKE FAIR FLORAMELL
 Henry Lawes
Cleander: Awake, awake, fair Floramell.
Floramell: I do.
Clea:	But who freed thee from this enchanted spell?
Flor:	'Twas you, such heavenly Chemistry you taught,
             From earth sublimed my purer thoughts.
Chorus:	Happy, thrice happy those who govern Fate,
             Subjecting greater minds to meaner state.
Clea:	And how appears earth's glories now?
Flor:	They're gone.
Clea:	Then on, fly, lest they once more dazzle thee.
Flor:	I run and undisturbed my flocks I'll find,
             There guide them with a quiet mind.
Chorus:	Happy, thrice happy those can see and try
             The world's fond glories so, and pass them by.
Clea:	But teil me, canst thou thus retire?
Flor:	I can.
Clea:	But when? Will not those hasty vows expire?
Flor:	Fond man, 'tis now the soul's affections more
             Etherial flames, diviner love.
Chorus:	Happy, thrice happy soul that ravish'd so,
             Enjoys a second heaven here below.]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Bm_prg/pyr_CH_Bm_prg-1409.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿WHEN DEATH SHALL SNATCH US
William Lawes
Dorinda:	When death shall snatch us from these kids,
             And shut up our divided lids,
             Thirsis, o teil me, prithee do Whither thou and I shall go.
Thirsis:	To Elizium,
Dorinda:	But where is't?
Thirsis:	A chaste soul can never miss't,
Dorinda:	I know no way but to my home,
             Is our cell Elizium?
Thirsis:	Cast thy face to yonder sky,
             There the milky path doth lie.
Both:	'Tis a straight and easy way,
             That leads to everlasting day.
Dorinda:	There birds may perch, but how can I,
             That have no wings and cannot fly?
Thirsis:	O do not sigh dear nymph, for fire
             That hath no wings still doth aspire,
             But tili it knock against the pole Heaven is the centre of the soul.
Dorinda:	But in Elizium how do they
             Pass eternity away?
Thirsis:	They know not what it is to fear,
             Free from the wolf, and horrid bear,
             There their lambs are always full.
Both:	Grass mor softer than our wool;
             A fixed spring; a constant sun;
             A day that ever is begun;
             Oaten pipes like gold that play A never ceasing roundelay.
             Perpetua1 rivers there do flow,
             Flowerd live and garlands grow,
             Shepherds there bear equal sway,
             Every nymph is Queen of May.
             Why then should we here make delay,
             Since we may be as free as they?
IF THE DEEP SIGHS
John Ward / Michael Drayton
             If the deep sighs of an afflicted breast o’erwhelmed with sorrow, Or the rected eyes of a poor wretch with miseries oppressed,
            For whose complaints tears never could suffice, Have not the Power your deities to move, who shall e'er look for succour From above? From whom too long I tarried for relief, now ask But death, that only ends my grief.
            There's not a grove that wonders not my woe, nor not a river weeps Not at my tale, I hear the echoes wandering to and fro Resound my grief through every hill and dale. The birds and beasts, Yet in their simple kind, lament for me; no pity eise I find.
            And tears I find do bring no other good, but as new showers Increase the rising flood.
]]></page>
        <pb facs='CH_Bm_prg/pyr_CH_Bm_prg-1410.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿]]></page>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>