<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns='http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0'>
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>HEMU Conservatoire de Genève - Programme de concert</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <editionStmt>
        <edition>TEI P5.1 Edition</edition>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>
            <persName>Claudio Bacciagaluppi</persName>
            <persName>Paolo Boschetti</persName>
            <persName>Laurent Pugin</persName>
            <persName>Violeta Struijk van Bergen</persName>
            <persName>Rodolfo Zitellini</persName>
            <date when='2016-01'>Janvier 2016</date>
          </resp>
          <name>Bureau Suisse du RISM</name>
        </respStmt>
      </editionStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>
          <orgName xml:base='http://www.rism-ch.org'>Bureau Suisse du RISM</orgName>
        </publisher>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <idno type='collection'>ch_gc</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>
            <date when='19261118'>18/11/1926</date>
            [sans titre]
          </title>
          <series>None</series>
          <placeName>Genève, Salle du Conservatoire</placeName>
          <orgName role='holding'>
            Bibliothèque du Conservatoire de Musique de Genève; 
            <link target='http://www.cmusge.ch/contact_bibliotheque'/>
          </orgName>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <!-- all the content of the program in one paragraph -->
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_14/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_14-0476.tif'/>
        <date when='19261118'/>
        <name key='Campion, Thomas' type='person' role='cmp'>Campion, Thomas</name>
        <name key='Dolmetsch, Victor' type='person' role='cmp'>Dolmetsch, Victor</name>
        <name key='Wilson, Lane' type='person' role='cmp'>Wilson, Lane</name>
        <title/>
        <placeName key='Genève, Salle du Conservatoire'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿SALLE DU CONSERVATOIRE
      Jeudi 18 novembre 1926, à 20 h. 30
CONCERT
Muriel SMIT
                            Cantatrice, de Londres avec le concours de
Jeanne PERROTTET Frank CHOISY
      Pianiste	Violoniste
Professeur suppléant au Conservatoire	Dir. du Conservatoire pop. de Musique
PROGRAMME
1.	a) The peaceful westerne winde................Thomas Campion (1610)
  b)	My lytell prety one................................*** 15 5© j
   c)	Have you seen but a whyte lilie grow.	*** 1614 / “,h0Mur9enm”Br‘
  d)	A Pastoral....................... Carey (arr. Lane Wilson)
          Muriel SMITH.
I. a.
The peaceful westerne winde	The musicke-loving birds are come
The winter storms hath tam’d ;	From cliffes and rockes unknown,
And Nature in each kinde	To see the trees and briers bloom
The kind heat hath inflam’d ;	That late were overflowne.
The forward buds so sweetly breathe	____.
Th.. Heav n which v,ew> the,r pomp	WhV	„,y ton,cm ?
wj ï j c • 1 t ,	„ c	’ Am I the worst of men ?
   ou d f=»n be deckt w.th flowers.	0 beautie, be not thou accus’d
See how the morning smiles	Too justly in this case!
On her bright easterne hill;	Unkindly if true love be us’d,
And with soft steps beguiles	’Twill yield thee little grâce.
Them that lie slumb’ring still !	(By permission of Boosey k Co.)
I.	b.
            My lytell prety one — ray prety boni one.
            She is a jollie one, and gentle as can be.
           With a beck she com’st anon : With a wink she will be gone No doubt she is alone of ail that ever I see.
(By permission of Boosey k Co.]
I. c.
Have you seen but a whyte lillie grow Before rude hands had touch’d it !
Have you inarkt but the fall of the snow Before the Earth hath smucht it ?
Have you felt the wool of beaver
Or swansdown ever ?
Or have smelt of the bud of the bryer,
Or the nard in the fire,
Or have tasted the bag of the bee —
O	so whyte, O so soft, O so sweet is shee !
(By permission of Boosey k Co.]]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_14/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_14-0477.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿1
I.	d.
Flocks are sporting, doves are courting, Warbling thrushes sweetly sing,
Ah! Ah!
Joy and pleasure without measure Heralds in the lovely spring.
La la la la.
Gentle zéphyr, silent glades,
Purling streams and cooling shades, Senses charming, pain disarming,
Love each tender heart invades.
Dancing, singing, piping, springing,
With our mirth the valleys ring Ah ! Ah ! etc.
(By permission of Boosey k Co.)
2.	Sonate en mi bémol majeur (op. 31, n° 3) Beethoven
      I.	Allegro - II. Scherzo (allegro vivace)
      III. Menuetto (moderato e grazipso) - IV. Presto con fuoco.
        M11- Jeanne PERROTTET.
3.	a b c d) Four sacred songs, pour chant et
violon............................ Gustav Holst
  e f g) Three old English songs, pour chant
et violon.......................... Rebecca Clarke
        Muriel SMITH et M. Frank CHOISY.
                                                  III. a.
Jesu Sweet ! now will I sing to thee a song |of love longing Do in my heart a quick well spring Thee to love above ail thing.
Jesu Sweet ! my dim hearts gleam, Brighter than the sunnie beam —
As thou wert born in Bethlehem —
Make in me thy lové dream.
Je
Tl
esu Sweet ! my dark hearts light hon art day withouten night,
Give me strength and eke might,
For to loven thee aright.
Jesu Sweet ! well may He be That in thy bliss, Thy self shall see With Iovè cords, then draw thou me That I may come and dwell with thee.
My Soul is nought but fire and ice. And my body earth and wood. Pray we ail the Most High king,
                                   III. b.
Who is the Lord of our last doom — That He would give us just one thing, That we may, do His will.
III. c.
       I sing of a Màiden that matchless is King of ail kings was her son i-wis.
       He came ail so still where his mother was,
       As dew in April that falleth on grass,
       He came ail so still to his mothers bower,
       As dew in April that falleth on flower,
       He came ail so still where His mother lay,
       As dew in April that falleth on spray.
      Mother and Maiden was ner none but she Well may such a lady God’s mother be.
                                   III d.
My Léman is so true of love and full steadfast Yet seemeth ever new, His love is on us cast.
I	would that ail Him knew, and loved him firm and fast They never would it rue but happy be at last.
He lovingly abides altho’ I stay full long
He will me never chide altho’ I do the wrong
He Says, Behold My side and why on Rood I hung.
For My love leave thy pride and I thee underfong.
111	dwell with thee, belive, Léman under thy tree
May no pain ere me grieve, nor make me from thee flee
I	will in at thy sleeve ail in Thine heart to be
Mine heart shall burst and cleave ere untrue thou me see.
Woris from Mediæval Anthology.

It was a lover and his lass
With a hey and aho and ahey nonny no !
With a hey nonny nonny — no
That oer the green cornfields did pass,
In Spring-time — the only pretty ring-time When birds do sing, hey ding — ading,
[aaing
Sweet lovers love the spring.
          III. e.
 Old English Songs.
This Carol they began that hour
With a heyetc. : —
How that life was but a Flower In Spring-time etc. : —
Then pretty lovers take the time With a hey etc. —
For Love is crowned with the prime In spring-time etc...
III./.
Phyllis on the new made hay, Fair and lonely still she lay, Wasting ail the summer day, In melanchoy sighing.
Till Aminter came that way, And bid her cease repining.
Told her be had loved her long, Loved her well and loved too long. Phyllis feared he’ d do her wrong And feared to say she loved him. Till he swore in word and song She never need reprove him.
He had bought the wedding ring Many a bow and silken string Fit for queen or fit for king To show he truly loved her. Thus did he déclaré and sing. Until at last he moved her.
III. g.
A tailor had a little mouse Hi deddle — um — cum — feedle.
They live together in one house.
Hi — diddle — um — cum — feedle...
Hi — diddle — um — cum Ta — rum — tan — tum —
Through the town of Ramsey
Hi — diddle — um — cum — over the lea
Hi — diddle — um — cum — feedle.
The tailor thought his mouse was ill —
Hi diddle etc.
So he gave it half of one blue pill —
Hi diddle etc.
The tailor throught his mouse would die Hi diddle etc.
So he baked it in an apple pie Hi diddle etc. : —
                   The tailor throught his mouse was dead.
                      Hi diddle etc.
                     So he got another in its stead Hi diddle etc. !
a)	Clair de lune.....................)
b)	Danse de Puck....................j e uss^
c)	Retour de muletiers................ Déodat de Séverac
d)	Segovia (première audition)......... Roussel
     M11» Jeanne PERROTTET.
a)	The Soldier..............................................John Ireland
b)	Someone..................................................Maurice Besly
c)	Love went a riding................................Frank Bridge
d)	A prayer to Our Lady............................Donald Fry
e)	At the well....................... Richard Hageman
     Muriel SMITH.
V. a.
          If I should die, think only this of me :
                 That there’s some corner of a foreign field That is for ever England. There shall be
                  In that rich earth a richer dust concealed ;
         A dust whom England bore, shaped, made aware,
Gave, once, her flowers to love, her ways to roam,
          A body of England’s breathing English air,
                 Washed by the rivers, blest by suns of home.]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_14/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_14-0478.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿And think, this heart, ail evil shed away,	ï
A puise in the eternal mind, no less	*
    Gives somewhere back the thoughts by England given ;
                         Her sights and sounds ; dreams happy as her day ;
                   And laughter, learnt of friends ; and gentleness,
    In hearts at peace, under an English heaven.
                                                         Rupert Brooke.
    V. b.
                 Someone came knocking at my wee small door.
    Someone came knocking, I’m sure, I’m sure, I’tn sure.
                    I	listened, I opened, I looked to left and right,
    But naught there was a-stirring in the still dark night,
                   Only the busy beetle, tap, tap, tap, tap, tapping on the wall,
                   Only from the forest the screech owls call.
    Onlv the cricket whistling, when the dewdrops fall,
                   So î know not who came knoncking' at ail, at ail, at ail !
                                               Walter de la Mere.
                                                                      (By permission ot the Author.)
                  V. c.	Then ail the youths and the maidens cried :
                                                     “ Stay here with us, King of Kings. ”
   Love went a-riding over the earth,	But Love said “ No, for the horse I ride,
    On Pegasus he rode.	For the horse I ride has wings. ”
    The flowers before him sprang to birth	MAy Coleriece
   And the frozen rivers flowed.	(By permiS5ion ot winthrop Rogers.)
               V. d.	Ail wandering men abroad at night
                                                   Mary of Candies, give them light
     Look kindly where poor people are.	Make a wide space behind their bars Mary of Homes, keep trouble far.
     Shelter beneath thy cares wings	for prisoners, Mary of Stars
   Mary of Roses, ail young things	Shed balm on aching eyes that weep
   Keep children warm in wind and rains	in woods of summer, Mary of Sleep.
      Of cold wights, Mary of Counterpanes	pray for me as ï r;ng thy chimes
   Send us high skies, blue days and fair	Im my poor belfry, Mary of Rhymes.
       Mary of Swallows, bless the air.
•	When the two sisters go to fetch water.
•	They corne to this spot, and they smile
:	They must be aware of Somebody who stands behind the trees
î	Whenever they go to fetch water.
•
                  The two sisters whisper to each other when they pass this spot.
:	They must have guessed the secret of that Somebody
•	Who stands behind the trees
j	Whenever they go to fetch water.
                   Their pitchers lurch suddenly and water spills When they reach this spot.
    They must have found out that Somebody’s heart is beating.
                  Who stands behind the trees Whe never they go to fetch water.
                   The two sisters glance at each other When they corne to this spot and they smile There is a laughter in their swift stepping feet Which makes confusion in Somebody’s mind Who stands behind the trees Whenever they go to fetch water.
                                               Rabinradath Tagore.
          (From an old Indian custom, that when a youth finds the girl he wishes to marry. he goes to the well, where she |comes daily for water. He pro poses to her, by knocking the pitcher ofF her head and smashing it to pieces.)
               Piano G A VEA U aux soins de MM. Sautier et Jaeger.]]></page>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>