<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns='http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0'>
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>HEMU Conservatoire de Genève - Programme de concert</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <editionStmt>
        <edition>TEI P5.1 Edition</edition>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>
            <persName>Claudio Bacciagaluppi</persName>
            <persName>Paolo Boschetti</persName>
            <persName>Laurent Pugin</persName>
            <persName>Violeta Struijk van Bergen</persName>
            <persName>Rodolfo Zitellini</persName>
            <date when='2016-01'>Janvier 2016</date>
          </resp>
          <name>Bureau Suisse du RISM</name>
        </respStmt>
      </editionStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>
          <orgName xml:base='http://www.rism-ch.org'>Bureau Suisse du RISM</orgName>
        </publisher>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <idno type='collection'>ch_gc</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>
            Troisième concert
            <date when='19260420'>20/04/1926</date>
          </title>
          <series>Troisième concert</series>
          <placeName>Genève, Salle du Conservatoire</placeName>
          <orgName role='holding'>
            Bibliothèque du Conservatoire de Musique de Genève; 
            <link target='http://www.cmusge.ch/contact_bibliotheque'/>
          </orgName>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <!-- all the content of the program in one paragraph -->
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_14/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_14-0256.tif'/>
        <date when='19260420'/>
        <name key='Byrd, William' type='person' role='cmp'>Byrd, William</name>
        <name key='Gibbons, Orlando' type='person' role='cmp'>Gibbons, Orlando</name>
        <name key='Morley, Thomas' type='person' role='cmp'>Morley, Thomas</name>
        <name key='Pilkington, Francis' type='person' role='cmp'>Pilkington, Francis</name>
        <name key='Weelkes, Thomas' type='person' role='cmp'>Weelkes, Thomas</name>
        <name key='Wilbye, John' type='person' role='cmp'>Wilbye, John</name>
        <name key='Banchieri, Adriano' type='person' role='cmp'>Banchieri, Adriano</name>
        <name key='Pont, Jacques du' type='person' role='cmp'>Pont, Jacques du</name>
        <name key='Purcell, Henry' type='person' role='cmp'>Purcell, Henry</name>
        <name key='Vaughan Williams, Ralph' type='person' role='cmp'>Vaughan Williams, Ralph</name>
        <title>Troisième concert</title>
        <placeName key='Genève, Salle du Conservatoire'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿«NOUVELLES AUDITIONS»
SAISON 1925—1926
*
Salle du Conservatoire ardi 20 Avril 1926, à 201k heures précises
TROISIÈME CONCERT
avec le concours des
“ENGLISH SINGERS”
sous l’aimable patronage de
Sir Eric et Lady Drummond Sir Herbert et Lady Ames Mr. et Mrs. Butler]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_14/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_14-0257.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿P R O G RAM M E
 Motets
Praise our Lord........William Byrd
Ave verum.........William Byrd
 Hosanna to the Son of David.....Thomas Weelkes
 Madrigals and a Ballet
 Flora gave me fairest flowers..... John Wilbye
 O	softly-singing Lute......Francis Pilkington
Though Amaryllis........William Byrd
On the plains.........Thomas Weelkes
Stay, Corydon........ John Wilbye
 Folk Songs .... arranged by R. Vaughan-Williams The Turtle Dove	Ca’ the Yowes
 The Dark-eyed Sailor	Wassail Song
 Italian Street Cries
 Intermedio di Spazzacamini.....Jacques Du Pont
 Intermedio di Solfanari......Adriano Banchieri
Cald’ Arost’.........Jacques Du Pont
 Duets and Trio
I spy Celia.........Henry Purcell
 John, come kiss me now (16th century), arranged by E. W. Naylor The Three Fairies........Henry Purcell
 Madrigals, a Ballet, and a Canzonet
The Silver Swan........Orlando Gibbons
 Now is the month of maying.....Thomas Morley
 I	go before, my darling......Thomas Morley
 My Phyllis bids me pack away ....	Thomas Weelkes
2

The Composers
William Byrd ...	1543—1623
Orlando Gibbons ...	1583—1625
Thomas Morley ...	1558—1603 Francis Pilkington - c. 1600
Thomas Weelkes ...	1575—1623
John Wilbye ....	1574—1638
Adriano Banchieri - -	1565—1634 Jacques Du Pont -
Henry Purcell ...	1658—1695
Ralph Vauglian-Williams -	1872
The English Singers
Flora Mann	Norman Stone
Nellie Carson Norman Notley Lillian Berger Cuthbert Kelly]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_14/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_14-0258.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿
Motets
Psalm for six voices
                      Praise our Lord, ail ye Gentiles,
                      Praise Him, ail ye people,
  Because His mercy is confirmed upon us,
                     And His truth remaineth for ever. Amen.
                                      Psalm CXVII.
Motet for four voices
                      Ave verum corpus, natum De Maria Virgine Vere passum, immolatum In cruce pro homine Cujus latus perforatum Unda fluxit sanguine.
                       Esto nobis praegustatum In mortis examine,
                          O	dulcis, o pie, o Jesu fili Maria miserere mei.
Motet for six voices........Thomas Weelkes
       Hosanna to the Son of David: blessed be the King that cometh in the Name of the Lord, Hosanna ! Hosanna ! Thou that sittest in the highest heavens. Hosanna in excelsis deo !
William Byrd
William Byrd
Madrigals and a Ballet
John Wilbye
                         Flora gave me fairest flowers,
  None so fair in Flora’» treasure,
                         These I plaeed on Phillis’ bowers,
  She was pleased and she my pleasure.
                       Smiling meadows seem to say,
                        Come, ye wantons, here to play.
Madrigal for five voices
5]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_14/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_14-0259.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿Madrigal for six voices - -
O	softly-singing Lute,
See with my tears thou time do keep. Yet softly, gentle strings,
Agree with Love that cannot sleep.
- - - Francis Pilkington
Sorrow hist whenas it sings.
When tears do fall then sighs arise.
So grief oft shines in most sad eyes, Yea love through heart it dies, it dies.
Madrigal for five voices - -
Though Amaryllis dance in green,
Like fairy queen;
And sing full clear
Corinna can, with smiling eheer,
Yet since their eyes make heart so sore, Heigh ho, heigh ho, l’il love no more.
William Byrd
Love ye who list, I force him not, Sith God it wot,
The more I wail,
The less my sighs and tears prevail. What shall I do but say therefore, Heigh ho, heigh ho, Fil love no more.
Ballet for five voices
On the plains Fairy trains
Were a-treading measures; Satyrs played,
Fairies stayed As the stops set leisures. Fa la la.
Thomas Weelkes
Nymphs begin To come in
Quickly thick and three-fold; Now they dance,
Now they pranee Present there to behold.
     Fa la la.
Madrigal for six voices -
Stay, Corydon, thou swain,
Talk not so soon of dying,
What though thy heart be slain, What though thy love be flying.
.....John Wilbye
She threatens thee but dares not strike, Thy nymph is light and shadow-like;
For if thou follow her, she’ll fly from thee, But if thou fly from her she’ll follow thee.
Folk SongS	arranged by R. Vaughan-Williams
                      The Turtle Dove
Fare ye well, my dear, I must be gone And leave you for a while;
If I roam away Fil come back again Though I roam ten thousand miles.
As fair thou art, my bonny lass,
So deep in love am I;
But I never will prove false to the bonny lass I love Till the stars fall from the sky.
The sea will never run dry, my dear, Nor the rocks never melt with the sun; But I never will prove false to the bonny lass I love Till ail these things be done.
O	yonder doth sit that little turtle dove He doth sit on yonder high tree, A-making a moan for the loss of his love As I will do for thee.
The Dark-eyed Sailor
It was a comely young lady fair Was walking out for to take the air; She met a sailor ail on her way,
So I paid attention to what they did say.
Said William, “ Lady, why walk alone? The night is coming and the day near gone.”
She said, while tears from her eyes did fall, “ It’s a dark-eyed sailor that’s proving my downfall.”
“ It’s two long yeaTs since he left the land;
He took a gold ring from ofT my hand;
We broke the token, here’s part with me
And the other lies rolling at the bottom of the sea.”
Then half the ring did young William show,
She was distracted midst joy and woe.
“ O welcome, William, I’ve lands and gold
For my dark-eyed sailor, so manly, true and bold.”
Then in a village down by the sea They joined in wedloek and well agree. So maids be true while your love’s away, For a cloudy morning brings forth a shining day.
 Ca’ the Yowes
Ca’ the yowes tae the knowes,
Ca’ them whar the heather grows, Ca’ them whar the burnie rows, My bonnie dearie.
Hark ! the mavis’ evening sang Sounding Clouden’s woods ainang, Then a-fauldin’ let us gang,
My bonnie dearie.
Fair and lovely as thou art,
Thou hast stown my very heart;
I	can die—but canna part,
My bonnie dearie.
While waters wimple to the sea:
While day blinks in the lift sae hie;
Till clay-cauld death shall blin’ my e’e, Ye shall be my dearie.
Ca’ the yowes tae the knowes...
Robert Burns-
Wassail Song
Wassail, Wassail, ail over the town Our bread it is white and our aie it is brown,
Our bowl it is made of the green maple tree,
In the wassail bowl we’ll drink unto thee.
Here’s a health to the ox and to his right
       eye,
Pray God send our master a good Christ-mas pie,
A good Christmas pie as e’er I did see, In the wassail bowl we’ll drink unto thee.
7]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_14/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_14-0260.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿Here’s a health to the ox and to his right horn,
Pray God send our master a good crop of corn,
A good crop of corn as e’er I did see,
In the wassail bowl we’ll drink unto thee.
Here’s a health to the ox and to his long tail,
Pray God send our master a good cask of aie,
A good cask of aie as e’er I did see,
In the wassail bowl we’ll drink unto thee.
Come, butler, come fill us a bowl of the best,
Then I pray that your soul in heaven may rest;
But if you do bring us a bowl of the small,
May the devil take butler, bowl and ail !
Then here’s to the maid in the lily-white smock,
Who tripped to the door and slipped back the lock;
Who tripped to the door and pulled back the pin
For to let those jolly wassailers walk in.
  Interval,
Italian Street Cries
Intermedio di Spazzacamini.....Jacques Du Pont
                        O	la bella brigada Hù hù spazzacami!
                       Nu sem dalla vallada Dov’ nass’ i bon facchi.
                       E sgurarem e fregarcm Coi smozzegù i vos cami E farem prest’ perô con quest’
                        Sia parecchia furmai e pà.
                          E tutto quest’ farem per un carli Bella brigad’ hù hù, spazzacami.
Intermedio di Solfanari......Adriano Banchieri
    Strazz’ e ciabatte, donne, ai solfanelli!
                      Sù, che son bianchi e belli
                      I	mazzi grossi e i canonzin sottili Legati con buon’ fili.
                      II	zolfo verde e questo non è gioco S’accenderan con fuoco
                      Sù che son bianchi e belli
                       Strazz’ e ciabatte, donne, ai solfanelli!
Cald' Arost’
Jacques du Pont
Cald’ arost’, cald’ e cott’ e vien’ adess’ .
Chi le vuol cald’ e cott’ adess’ :
E tond’ e mond’ e largh’ in fond E strett’ in cim’ e bianch’ in mezz’ e crep’ adess’, E cott’ arost’ e mond’ e tost,
Chi le vuol caldî e cott’ adess’.
Cinque, e cinque diec’ e cinque quindici,
E cinque vent’ e cinque venticinqu’ e cinque trenta, E vienne l’altra !
Duets and Trio
I spy Celia
Henry Purcell
I spy Celia; Celia eyes me.
I approach her; but she flies me.
I pursue; more coy I find her.
I	seem colder; then she’s kinder.
Her eyes charm me; my words move her. She esteems me; and I love her.
In not blessing most she blesses,
And not possessing, each possesses. Now she blushes, I grow bolder. She would leave me, but I hold her. She grows angry, I appease her.
I	am redder, then I please her.
16th Century
John, corne kiss me now ------ arrangedbyE.W.Naylor
                      Wife
                      John, come kiss me now,
                     John, come kiss me by and by,
                    And make no more ado.
                    Husband
                      Peace, I’m angry now,
                       Peace, I’m angry at the heart And know not what to do.
9]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_14/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_14-0261.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿   Wives can faine and wives can flatter, Have I not hit them now,
   When once they begin they still do chatter,
   And so does my wife too.
  m/e
   And wives have many fair words and looks,
   And draw silly men on folly’s hooks, John, come kiss me now.
Husband
   Now of my song l’il makc an end. Lo, here, I quit thee now,
   Ail evil wives to the devil I send, Among them my wife too.
The Three Fairies
Henry Purcell
When the cock begins to crow
And the embers leave to glow
And the owl cries Tu-whit Tu-whoo,
When crickets do sing
And mice roam about
And midnight bells ring
To call the devout;
When the lazy lie sleeping And think it no harm,
Their zeal is so cold,
And their beds are so warm.
When the long lazy slut
Has not made the parlour clean,
No water on the hearth is put,
But ail things in disorder seem; Then we trip it round the room And make like bees a drowsy hum. Be she Betty, Nan or Sue,
We make her of another hue,
And pinch her black and blue.
Madrigals, a Ballet, and a Canzonet
Madrigal for five voices - - ■
The Silver Swan, who, living, had no note, When death approached, unlocked her silent throat,
Leaning her breast against the reedy shore,
Orlando Gibbons
Thus sung her first and last, and sung no more.
“ Farewell ail joys, O Death, come close mine eyes,
More geese than swans now live, more fools than wise.”
Ballet for five voices
Thomas Morley
Now is the month of maying, When merry lads are playing Each with his bonny lass, Upon the greeny grass.
 Fa la la.
The spring clad ail in gladness,
Doth laugh at winter’s sadness,
And to the bagpipes’ Sound The nymphs tread out their ground, Fa la la.
                       Fie then ! why sit we musing, Youth’s sweet delight refusing? Say dainty nymphs, and speak, Shall we play barley-break?
                                    Fa la la.
Canzonet for two voices........Thomas Morley
                       I	go before, my darling,
                        Foliow thou to the bower in the close alley:
                       There we will together
                        Sweetly kiss each other,
                       And like two wantons dally.
Thomas Weelkes
                     My Phyllis bids me pack away.
                      And yet she holds me in delay;
                       I,	weeping, cry my heart will break;
                       She tells me no, I need not speak.
                       Then if my fortune falls not wrong
                       I	need not sing another song.
Madrigal for six voices
11]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_14/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_14-0262.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿]]></page>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>