<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?> 
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?> 
<TEI xmlns='http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0'>
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>HEMU Conservatoire de Genève - Programme de concert</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <editionStmt>
        <edition>TEI P5.1 Edition</edition>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>
            <persName>Claudio Bacciagaluppi</persName>
            <persName>Paolo Boschetti</persName>
            <persName>Laurent Pugin</persName>
            <persName>Violeta Struijk van Bergen</persName>
            <persName>Rodolfo Zitellini</persName>
            <date when='2016-01'>Janvier 2016</date>
          </resp>
          <name>Bureau Suisse du RISM</name>
        </respStmt>
      </editionStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>
          <orgName xml:base='http://www.rism-ch.org'>Bureau Suisse du RISM</orgName>
        </publisher>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <idno type='collection'>ch_gc</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>
            <date when='19020416'>16/04/1902</date>
             [sans titre] 
          </title>
          <series>None</series>
          <placeName>Salle des Amis de l'Instruction</placeName>
          <orgName role='holding'>
             Bibliothèque du Conservatoire de Musique de Genève; 
            <link target='http://www.cmusge.ch/contact_bibliotheque'/>
          </orgName>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <!-- all the content of the program in one paragraph -->
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_06/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_06-0087.tif'/>
        <date when='19020416'/>
        <date when='19020423'/>
        <name key='Pascal, Florian' type='person' role='cmp'>Pascal, Florian</name>
        <title/>
        <placeName key='Genève, Salle des amis de l&apos;Instruction'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿Price : 50 centimes.
SALLE DES AMIS DE L’INSTRUCTION
  “ The Jewel Maiden ”
Libretto by M. C. GILLINGTON | Music by Florian PASCAL Orchestration by HALLAM SANDERSON
    Wednesday A.pril IG'11
          &
     Wednesday -A.jp l'il SCBrd 1 Î30C2 at S.15 p. m.
Dances arranged by JVT Oscar liŒWEJ'lTHflL» Costumes designed by JVP MACpflt^LiAJ'lE
Organist of the English Church
Most kindly assistée! in the orchestra by Mrs Aylmer Lloyd at the piano and other instrumentalists.
Tickets lo Le obtained from M. Rotschy, 22, Corraterie. tfeserved 5 frs 4 3 frs.
iiaparçeçe Operetta
MUSICAL DIHECTOR AND CONDUCTOR
JVlf Haltaiq SflflDERSOtf
                       l/nreserved 2 frs.
]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_06/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_06-0088.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿«	tJewel JVlaider) »
in 3 A et s
DRAM AT IS PERSO N Æ.
0 Haru San (disguised as a llower pedlar) . Miss Doris Macfarlane Kofugi (a fishermaiden betrothed lo Uroshima) Miss Nona Macfarlane Uroshima (a young flsherman) .... Mr Oscar Loewf.nthal The Tycoon (Emperor of Japan . . . . Mr L. Foxhall Lewis Matzukasé (a |»easant girl) . . . .. Miss Ruth Stokœ 0 Tatsu San (a maid of honour) .... Miss Ethel Macfarlane 0 Tori San (a maid of honour).... Miss Ruth Stokœ 0 Kiku San (a maid of iionuur)r .... Miss Emily Kofce»
18t Court Lady.........Miss Flora Macfarlane
2nd Court Lady.........Miss Bridges
                                          ! Miss Beaumont Peasant Girls	' Miss Gibbons
                                           ( Miss Byrnes f Miss Amy Marmion Three litlie dancing girls	j Miss Eveline Filliter
                                           ( Miss Flora Macfarlane Chorus of peasant and tisher' jfirls and flshermen, Court Ladies, Courtiers and Nuhian Slaves.
ACT I
A seafaring village of Enoshima.
Interval 15 minutes.
ACT II
           Tycoon’s Palace.	.
Interval of 25 minutes. Light refreshments may be had at the Buffet.
ACT III
Seventy years affcer. Village of Enoshima.
A song composed expressly for Mr Lewis by Mr Hallam Sanderson will be sung after the Tycoon’s entry in the second act, entitled «Fall softly dews of love. »
SYNOPSIS
ACT I
  Kofugi a lishermaiden is betrothed to Uroshima a flsherman, wlio lias unfortunately become enamoured of a flower girl, who visits the village once a year. Uroshima seekirtgfto lind oui lieridentity, implores lier to tell him, who slie is and from whence slie cornes O Haru San, tliinking they are alone, confesses herself to be the Jewel Maiden, danghter of theTycoon wlio guards the sacred jewels and dwells in the temple throûghout the year, only showing herself to the public wlien carrying the sacred jewels through the city. So trying became lier existence, that flnding a secret doorshe determined todress as a flower girl and visit at liberty the surrounding country. During tliis récital Kofugi enters and hearing ail, vows to be revenged, in that slie will take O Haru San’s place in the temple and at the Royal court. She is strenglhened in lier threat by hearing Uroshima swear eternal love, dévotion and servitude to the Princess.
ACT 11
When at Court many remarks arc made on Kofugi’s appearance.
O	Haru San re-appearing asserts ber rights and prays for forgiveness for herself and the imposter Kofugi.
ACT III
  Seventy two years bave elapsed and Uroshima the flsherman has solaced himself by linding the Fortunate Isles and returns 011 the Day of the Dead to his native village unawareof the lapse of time and tliat lie now an old man. lie is told this by the peasants, also that Kofugi is is dead and that a new Tycoon reigns. On looking down the Street Uroshima sees an ancient lady whom lie discovers to be t lie former Jewel Maiden of his youth and amid the dancing of the new génération the old pair leave the village hand in liand to find together the Fortunate Isles of everlasting happiness.]]></page>
        <pb facs='Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_06/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_06-0089.tif'/>
        <page><![CDATA[﻿ANALYSE
Ier ACTE
   Une liIle de pécheur, Kofugi, est fiancée à Uroshima, pêcheur aussi ; celui-ci est malheureusement tombé amoureux d’une jeune marchande de fleurs, Ostaru San, qui passe par le village une fois par an. Uroshima, cherchant à découvrir son identité, l’implore de lui dire qui elle est et d’où elle vient. Ostaru San, croyant <|u’ils sont seuls, confesse qu’elle est la Jeune Fille aux Joyaux, fille du Jaïcoun, chargée delà garde des joyaux sacrés; elle habite le temple toute l’année, ne se montrant qu’une seule fois, quand les joyaux sacrés sont portés à travers la ville; son existence est devenue si monotone qu’ayant découvert an temple une porte secrète, elle s’est décidée à se déguiser en marchande de fleurs et à parcourir ainsi les environs quand bon lui semble. Pendant ce récit Kofugi entre et entend tout; elle jure de se venger en s’emparant de la place de Ostaru San dans le temple et à la cour royale. Çlle est affermie dans son désir en entendant Uroshima jurer amour éternel, dévotion et soumission à la princesse.
Urne ACTE
   Quand Kofugi est à la cour, bien des remarques sont faites sur sa contenance. Ostaru San fait sa réapparition et affirme ses droits; elle demande le pardon de son père pour elle et pour l’imposteur.
III™ ACTE
   Soixante-douze ans se sont écoulés; Uroshima le pécheur a trouvé une con&Jation à sa douleui dans ’a découverte qu'il a faite des lie-» fortunées; il revient dans son village natal et y arrive le Jour des morts, inconscient du temps qui s’est écoulé depuis son départ et ne se doutant pas qu’il est maintenant un vieillard. Les paysans le lui apprennent, ils lui apprennent aussi que Kotugi est morte et qu’un nouveau Jaïcoun régne. A ce moment Uroshima voit s’avancer une femme âgée qu’il découvre être l’ancienne jeune fille aux joyaux de sa jeunesse et au milieu des danses de la jeune génération le vieux couple quitte le village la main dans la main pour aller ensemble aux Iles fortunées où le bonheur est éternel.]]></page>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>