<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
            <title>HEMU Conservatoire de Genève - Programme de concert</title>
        </titleStmt>
        <editionStmt>
            <edition>TEI P5.1 Edition</edition>
            <respStmt>
                <resp>
                    <persName>Claudio Bacciagaluppi</persName>
                    <persName>Paolo Boschetti</persName>
                    <persName>Laurent Pugin</persName>
                    <persName>Violeta Struijk van Bergen</persName>
                    <persName>Rodolfo Zitellini</persName>
                    <date when="2016-01">Janvier 2016</date>
                </resp>
                <name>Bureau Suisse du RISM</name>
            </respStmt>
        </editionStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
            <publisher><orgName xml:base="http://www.rism-ch.org">Bureau Suisse du RISM</orgName></publisher>
        </publicationStmt>
	    <seriesStmt>
	     <idno type="collection">ch_gc</idno>
	    </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
		<bibl>
        <title><date when="19051109">09/11/1905</date></title>
<series>None</series>
<placeName>Genève, Grande salle du Conservatoire</placeName>
<orgName role="holding">Bibliothèque du Conservatoire de Musique de Genève; <link target="http://www.cmusge.ch/contact_bibliotheque"/></orgName>

		</bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
        <p> <!-- all the content of the program in one paragraph -->
            <pb facs="Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_06/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_06-1049.tif"/>
<date when="19051109"/>
<name key="Bach, Johann Sebastian" type="person" role="cmp">Johann Sebastian Bach</name>
<name key="Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus" type="person" role="cmp">Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart</name>
<name key="Olsen, Ole" type="person" role="cmp">Olsen, Ole</name>
<name key="Sinding, Christian" type="person" role="cmp">Sinding, Christian</name>
<name key="Wieniawski, Henryk" type="person" role="cmp">Wieniawski, Henryk</name>
<name key="Liszt, Franz" type="person" role="cmp">Liszt, Franz</name>
<name key="Beethoven, Ludwig van" type="person" role="cmp">Ludwig van Beethoven</name>
<name key="Moszkowski, Moritz" type="person" role="cmp">Moszkowski, Moritz</name>
<name key="Hubay, Jenö" type="person" role="cmp">Hubay, Jenö</name>
<name key="Chopin, Fryderyk" type="person" role="cmp">Chopin, Fryderyk</name>
<name key="Grieg, Edvard" type="person" role="cmp">Grieg, Edvard</name><title/>
<placeName key="Genève, Grande salle du Conservatoire"/>
<name key="None" type="series"/>
<page><![CDATA[﻿ GRANDE SALLE DU CONSERVATOIRE
       Jeudi 9 novembre 1905, à 8 heures et quart du soir
CONCERT
DONNÉ PAR
Le petit Harold COLOMBATTI
                           (âgé de 8 ans)
                 AVEC LE GRACIEUX CONCOURS DE
M"" IM.-L. DEBOGIS-BOHY M. Robert POLLAK
CANTATRICE	VIOLONISTE
     ACCOMPAGNATEUR : M. L. COLOMBATTI
                 PROFESSEUR AU CONSERVATOIRE
          ----«H-
        PRIX DES PLACES :
    Réservées, 5 fr. — Premières, 3 fr. — Galerie, 1 fr.
           Billets au Conservatoire et chez Mmes Chouet & Gaden.]]></page>
<pb facs="Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_06/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_06-1050.tif"/>
<page><![CDATA[﻿OPINION DE LA PRESSE
The Brighton Standard and Fashionable Visitors’ List
Aug. 1, 1905
    Brighton Palace Fier. — As it was, the major interest of the afternoon centred in the achievements of a small boy of Italian parentage, Master Harold Colombatti, who, boasting precocious gifts as a pianist, is the latest recruit to the army of juvenile prodigies with which the English concert halls have been flooded during the last year or two. His father is a professor at the Geneva Conservatoire, and so the little fellow’s talent is undoubtedly hereditary. He is obviously no older than the eight years with which they crédit him, and therefore it was rather amazing to note the extent of his mastery over the keyboard. He looks rather a delicate child, with somewhat girlish features, emphasised by long, though by no means flowing hair of a dark chestnut shade, and it was therefore natural, perhaps, that his touch should be remarkable less for firmness than nimbleness. But he played with the stylishness, confidence and précision, as well as the intelligence, of the precocious little musician he is. Part of an old-fashioned sonata of Mozart’s, with its symmetrical, clean-cut phrases, and polished impeccably respectable rhythms, was rippled off lightly, easily and smoothly, and afterwards he dashed off a taking little valse with sprightly verve and gaiety. Without presenting any technical difficulty, it served as a vehicle for the display of no little brilliance and elastcity of musical movement, and the little pianist accepted the hearty applause that greeted him with child-like self-possession and came back to play an encore piece that strengthened one’s interest in his naturally immature but still remarkably promising powers.
The Bexill Chronicle
Saturday, August, 26, 1005
    A wonderful boy pianist. — Another infant prodigy visited the Kursaal on wednesday afternoon. This was Master Harold Colombatti, who is the youngest pianist of the day appearing in public. He is only 8 */2 years old, and he looks younger. But he is a wonderful pianist. For a lad of his tender years, his performance was really marvellous, and his hearers were delighted. The lad is a genius, and if his ability as a musician increases in proportion to increasing years, he will be a second Paderewsky. His sélections included “Préludé ” (Bach),“Sonata” (Mozart), “Valse” (Chopin), “ Thème et Variation” (Beethoven), “Moulin” and “Jour de Noce” (Grieg). For the last two items he was enthusiastically encored.
                                                  \
Brighton Gazette
3 Août 1905
    Concert du Palace Pier Théâtre. — Un grand succès digne d’être noté fut celui du petit Harold Colombatti. Son interprétation sur le piano des œuvres des grands maîtres l’a révélé comme un véritable artiste avec un brillant avenir.
Sussex Daily News
31 Juillet 1905
    L’auditoire était tout-à-fait enthousiasmé des productions sur le piano du petit Harold Colombatti. Pour un si jeune pianiste son interprétation de Mozart, Beethoven, etc., était véritablement artistique. Inutile d’ajouter qu’il a été chaleureusement acclamé.
PROGRAMME
 ---X- —
 PREMIÈRE PARTIE
1.	a) Petit Prélude..........Bach.
b)	Sonate (fragment)........Mozart.
c)	Papillons...........Ole Olsen.
        Harold Golombatti.
2.	a) Romance...........Sinding.
b)	Mazurka...........Wieniawski.
           M. R. Pollak.
3.	a) Joie ou douleur........)
  b)	Enfant, si j’étais Roi......\ ' ISZT‘
          Mme Debogis-Bohy.
4.	a) Thème et Variations.......Beethoven.
b)	Danse Espagnole (à 4 mains).....Moskowsky.
           Harold Colombatti et M. E. Colombatti.
 deuxième partie
5.	Heire Kati...........Hubay.
           M. R. Pollak.
6.	a) Nocturne..........) _
/ „ ,	[ Chopin.
b)	Valse...........)
           Harold Colombatti.
7.	Mazurka............Chopin.
          Mme Debogis-Bohy.
8.	Jour de Noces..........Grieg.
           Harold Colombatti.]]></page>
<pb facs="Gc_prg/CH_Gc_prg_06/pyr_CH_Gc_prg_06-1051.tif"/>
<page><![CDATA[﻿]]></page>
       
        </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
